原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
时间轴     壬虚浪影  知之  caroline
时间轴     今  没有影子  西·查  Ans
翻译     肉松  辰星晓  伊森泽生  杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译     子V  苏葵  TracyOY  幽冥部落  贝七
翻译     Z小花儿  米糊  江夏  余欢
翻译     Giggles  kathy567  陈奥奥  布塔
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我是你们的国王  乔治三世
this is your king, George III.
校对     布塔的肝
欢迎欣赏《汉密尔顿》
Welcome to Hamilton.
汉密尔顿
后期     渔夫
现在
At this time,
总监     布塔
请各位将手机和其他电子设备静音
please silence all cell phones and other electronic devices.
严禁任何拍摄与录制
All photography and video recording is strictly prohibited.
纽约市
2016年6月
谢谢  请开始欣赏
Thank you, and enjoy my show.
里查德·罗杰斯剧院
私生之子  孤苦之人
How does a bastard, orphan
荡妇之子  苏格兰人
Son of a whore and a Scotsman
生于加勒比被人遗忘的角落
Dropped in the middle of a forgotten spot in the Caribbean
出身贫寒  生活穷迫
By providence, impoverished, in squalor
竟想成为  英雄学者
Grow up to be a hero and a scholar?
脸印上十美元  国父没有父亲
The ten-dollar, founding father without a father
开辟道路  砥砺奋进
Got a lot farther by working a lot harder
发挥才智
By being a lot smarter
白手起家
By being a self-starter
年方十四  掌管远洋贸易
By 14, they placed him in charge of a trading charter
日日夜夜  无数黑人奴隶
And every day, while slaves
惨遭屠杀  通过海运买卖
Were being slaughtered and carted away across the waves
他却警醒  不甘同流合污
He struggled and kept his guard up
内心渴望  与之同仇敌忾
Inside, he was longing for something to be a part of
这位兄台  不惜强取豪夺
The brother was ready to beg, steal, borrow or barter
飓风来袭  家乡满目疮痍
Then a hurricane came and devastation reigned
1772年飓风袭击圣克罗伊岛
少年汉密尔顿给父亲写信
详细描述灾难场景  并匿名登报发表
得到乡绅们的赏识  实现用笔墨开拓出路
他的未来  千钧一发之际
Our man saw his future drip, dripping down the drain
细细思忖  笔尖灵感迸发
Put a pencil to his temple, connected it to his brain
初次行文  写出悲痛经历
And he wrote his first refrain, a testament to his pain
消息传开  说他天赋异禀
Well, the word got around, they said, "This kid is insane, man"
乡亲善款  将他送去北美
Took up a collection just to send him to the mainland
"好好学习  勿忘你的出身
"Get your education, don't forget from whence you came
世人将你铭记
And the world's gonna know your name
你叫什么"
What's your name, man?
亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Alexander Hamilton
我叫亚历山大·汉密尔顿
My name is Alexander Hamilton
志向千千万  我才刚开始
And there's a million things I haven't done
你们等着瞧
But just you wait
Just you wait
年方十岁  父亲欠债离家
When he was ten, his father split, full of it, debt-ridden
两年过后  母子卧病不起
Two years later, see Alex and his mother bedridden, half dead
满身污物  恶臭令人窒息
Sittin' in their own sick, the scent thick and...
亚历山大好转  母亲一命呜呼
Alex got better but his mother went quick
投靠表亲  表亲却寻短见
Moved in with a cousin, the cousin committed suicide
徒留灰心丧气  心中响起
Left him with nothing but ruined pride. Something new inside
新的声音
A voice saying
"亚历山大  你得自食其力"
"Alex, you gotta fend for yourself"
另辟蹊径  选择饱读诗书
He started retreatin' and readin' every treatise on the shelf
没有知识  他将一事无成
There would've been nothing left to do for someone less astute
欠债不还  他会穷困而亡
He would've been dead or destitute without a cent of restitution
开始工作  服务亡母地主
Started working, clerking for his late mother's landlord
交易糖酒  他都负担不起
Tradin' sugarcane and rum and all the things he can't afford
手不释卷  一本都不放过
Scammin' for every book he can get his hands on
规划未来  逐渐得以立足
Plannin' for the future see him now as he stands on
轮船驶向  新的大陆
The bow of a ship headed for a new land
人到纽约  改头换面
In New York you can be a new man
你们等着瞧
Just you wait
人到纽约  改头换面
In New York you can be a new man
你们等着瞧
Just you wait
人到纽约  改头换面
In New York you can be a new man
人到纽约  人到纽约
In New York, New York
你们等着瞧
Just you wait
亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Alexander Hamilton
我们期盼你
We are waiting in the wings for you
Waiting in the wings for you
你从不言弃
You could never back down
你急不可待
You never learned to take your time
亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Alexander Hamilton
美利坚歌颂你时
When America sings for you
会否知晓  你的辉煌经历
Will they know what you overcame?
会否知晓  你将历史改写
Will they know you rewrote the game?
世界从此不同
The world will never be the same
船已驶入港口
The ship is in the harbor now
你能否看到他
See if you can spot him
你们等着瞧
Just you wait
又一位移民白手起家
Another immigrant comin' up from the bottom
你们等着瞧
Just you wait
敌人玷污他的名声  美利坚遗忘他
His enemies destroyed his rep, America forgot him
我们与他同抗争
We fought with him
我为他牺牲自己
Me, I died for him
我信任他
Me, I trusted him
我爱戴他
Me, I loved him
我
And me
我是傻瓜  射杀了他
I'm the damn fool that shot him
射杀了他
Shot him, shot him
志向千千万  我才刚开始
There's a million things I haven't done
你们等着瞧
But just you wait
你叫什么
What's your name, man?
亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Alexander Hamilton
1776年
纽约市
New York City
请问您是亚隆·伯尔吗
Pardon me, are you Aaron Burr, sir
要看是谁在问了
That depends who's asking
当然了  我是亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Oh, well, sure, sir, I'm Alexander Hamilton
为您效劳  先生
I'm at your service, sir
我一直在找您
I have been looking for you
我有点紧张了
I'm getting nervous
先生  我在普林斯顿就久仰大名
Sir, I heard your name at Princeton
我想尽快完成学业
I was seeking an accelerated course of study
当我跟您的校友商量这件事时
When I got sort of out of sorts with a buddy of yours
我可能打了他  记不清了
I may have punched him it's a blur, sir
他负责财务
He handles the financials
你打了财务长
You punched the bursar
对  我想步您的后尘
Yes. I wanted to do what you did
两年毕业  加入革命
Graduate in two then join the revolution
他的眼神说我在犯傻
He looked at me like I was stupid
我没犯傻
I'm not stupid
您怎么做到的
So, how'd you do it?
您怎么能提前毕业
How'd you graduate so fast?
这是我父母的遗愿
It was my parents' dying wish before they passed
您是孤儿  原来如此
You're an orphan, of course
我也是孤儿
I'm an orphan. God
但愿有一场战争
I wish there was a war
让我们能证明
Then we could prove that
自己的价值高于他人期望
we're worth more than anyone bargained for
请你喝一杯
Can I buy you a drink
那真不错
That would be nice
趁着聊天  我给你个建议
While we're talking, let me offer you some free advice
少说话
Talk less
什么
What
多微笑
Smile more
别向他们
Don't let them know
表露你的喜恶
What you're against or what you're for
此话当真
You can't be serious
你想出人头地
You wanna get ahead?
对
Yes
口无遮拦的傻瓜下场凄凉
Fools who run their mouths off wind up dead
什么时间
What time is it?
表演时间
Showtime!
如我所言
Like I said
表演时间  表演时间
Showtime! Showtime!
我是约翰·劳伦斯
I'm John Laurens in the place to be
喝了两扎啤酒
Had two pints of Sam Adams
努力提升酒量
But I'm workin' on three
那些英国兵与我不和
Those redcoats don't want it with me
因为我不争得独立誓不罢休
'Cause I will pop chick-a pop these cops till I'm free
没错  亲爱的  我是拉法耶特
Oui, oui, mon ami, je m'appelle Lafayette
革命骑士来也
The Lancelot of the revolutionary set
远道而来说"晚安"
I came from afar just to say, "Bonsoir"
向国王说"放马过来"
Tell the king "Casse-toi"
谁最强
Who is the best?
我最强
C'est moi
我是赫拉克勒斯·穆里根  有种就来
I am Hercules Mulligan, up in it, lovin' it
我听到你母亲喊着"再来一次"
Yes, I heard your mother said, "Come again?"
管好你们的女儿和马匹
Lock up your daughters and horses
身穿四套束腰  很难宽衣解带欢爱
Of course, it's hard to have intercourse over four sets of corsets
少说放荡话  再来一杯酒
No more sex, pour me another brew, son
再举杯敬革命
Let's raise a couple more to the revolution
这不是普林斯顿的奇才吗
Well, if it ain't the prodigy of Princeton College
亚隆·伯尔
Aaron Burr
唱一首  说一段
Give us a verse, drop some knowledge
祝好运  你表态
Good luck with, that you're takin' a stand
你上场  我欣赏
You spit, I'mma sit
看看谁笑到最后
We'll see where we land
伯尔  革命即将到来  你还犹豫什么
Burr, the revolution's imminent, what do you stall for
你从不表态  伯尔  你究竟相信什么
If you stand for nothing, Burr, what'll you fall for
你是谁
Who are you?
这小子是谁  他要干什么
Who is this kid? What's he gonna do?
我绝不放过良机
I am not throwing away my shot
我正如我的国家
Hey, yo, I'm just like my country
年轻  好斗  迫切
I'm young, scrappy and hungry
我绝不放过良机
And I'm not throwing away my shot
我会拿到国王学院的奖学金
I'mma get a scholarship to King's College
哥伦比亚大学的前身
我多半不该吹嘘
I probably shouldn't brag
真该死  我这么出色
But dag, I amaze and astonish
问题在于我脑筋灵光却不懂逢迎
The problem is I got a lot of brains but no polish
我得呐喊才有人肯听
I gotta holler just to be heard
我说的每句话都充满智慧
With every word, I drop knowledge
我是未经雕琢的璞玉  闪闪发光的煤炭
I'm a diamond in the rough, a shiny piece of coal
想方设法  实现目标
Tryin' to reach my goal
演说才能  无懈可击
My power of speech, unimpeachable
年方十九  思想成熟
Only 19, but my mind is older
纽约街道  愈发寒冷
These New York City streets get colder
肩担重任
I shoulder every burden
弥补缺点
Every disadvantage I have learned to manage
身无武器
I don't have a gun to brandish
忍饥挨饿
I walk these streets famished
我计划让这星星之火燎原
The plan is to fan this spark into a flame
真该死  天要黑了
But damn, it's getting dark
让我说出我的名字
So let me spell out the name
我是  亚  历  山  大
I am the A-l-e-x-a-n-d-e-r
我们  一  见  如  故
We are meant to be
本该自治的殖民地
A colony that runs independently
却被英国肆意欺负
Meanwhile, Britain keeps shittin' on us endlessly
关键他们收税无情无义
Essentially, they tax us relentlessly
转身就被乔治国王挥霍无理
Then King George turns around runs a spending spree
他绝不会解放他的后裔
He ain't ever gonna set his descendants free
本世纪内定有革命掀起
So there will be a revolution in this century
该我登场
Enter me
他请出自己
He says in parentheses
等你在历史课上学到我  不必讶异
And don't be shocked when your history book mentions me
我愿献出生命换取自由权利
I will lay down my life if it sets us free
最终你们会见证我出人头地
Eventually you'll see my ascendancy
我绝不放过良机
And I am not throwing away my shot
良机
My shot
我绝不放过良机
I am not throwing away my shot
良机
My shot
我正如我的国家
Hey, yo, I'm just like my country
年轻  好斗  迫切
I'm young, scrappy and hungry
我绝不放过良机
And I'm not throwing away my shot
I am not throwing away my shot
我绝不放过良机
我正如我的国家
Hey, yo, I'm just like my country
年轻  好斗  迫切
I'm young, scrappy and hungry
我绝不放过良机
And I'm not throwing away my shot
抓住良机  干杯
It's time to take a shot
我梦想摆脱君主制
I dream of life without a monarchy
法国的动乱将会导致"误政府"
The unrest in France will lead to "on-archy"
"误政府"  怎么说来着
"On-archy?" How you say?
无政府
Anarchy
等我参战  将让对手方寸大乱
When I fight I make the other side panicky
抓住良机
With my shot
我是裁缝学徒
Yo, I'm a tailor's apprentice
如同老爹  护着你们这几个愣头青
And I got y'all knuckleheads in loco parentis
我要加入反抗
I'm joining the rebellion
因为这是提升社会地位的坦途
'Cause I know it's my chance to socially advance
与其裁衣缝裤
Instead of sewin' some pants
不如抓住良机
I'm gonna take a shot!
但那都不算真正的自由
But we'll never be truly free
除非奴隶也同你我一般享有权利
Until those in bondage have the same rights as you and me
你和我  成功或成仁
You and I, do or die
等我骑着高头大马
Wait till I sally in on a stallion
领第一支黑人军队开拔
With the first black battalion
抓住良机
Have another shot
天才们  小声点
Geniuses, lower your voices
别惹麻烦  自会机遇多多
You keep out of trouble and you double your choices
我支持你们
I'm with you
但时局动荡
But the situation is fraught
得小心行事
You've got to be carefully taught
管不住嘴  就会丢掉生机
If you talk, you're gonna get shot
伯尔  看看在座贵客
Burr, check what we got
拉法耶特先生强硬不输圆桌骑士
Mr. Lafayette hard rock like Lancelot
你缝的裤子也不赖
I think your pants look hot
劳伦斯  你最得我认可
Laurens, I like you a lot
让我们一起为革命出谋划策
Let's hatch a plot blacker than the kettle callin' the pot
上天让我们齐聚一堂  这机会如此难得
What are the odds the gods would put us all in one spot
打破传统观念  不留情面
Poppin' a squat on conventional wisdom, like it or not
一群支持革命的废奴主义者
A bunch of revolutionary manumission abolitionists?
给我一个职位
Give me a position
带我领取弹药
Show me where the ammunition is
我是不是嗓门太大
Oh, am I talkin' too loud?
有时我过于激动  就会喋喋不休
Sometimes I get overexcited shoot off at the mouth
我从没有过这么多朋友
I never had a group of friends before
我保证会让你们骄傲
I promise that I'll make y'all proud
我们推他到人前去燥
Let's get this guy in front of a crowd
我绝不放过良机
I am not throwing away my shot
I am not throwing away My shot
我正如我的国家
Hey, yo, I'm just like my country
年轻  好斗  迫切
I'm young, scrappy and hungry
我绝不放过良机
And I'm not throwing away my shot
I am not throwing away my shot
我绝不放过良机
我正如我的国家
Hey, yo, I'm just like my country
年轻  好斗  迫切
I'm young, scrappy and hungry
我绝不放过良机
And I'm not throwing away my shot
大家一起唱
Everybody sing!
让他们听听
Say, let 'em hear ya!
来吧
Let's go!
让声浪掀翻屋顶
I said shout it to the rooftops!
掀翻屋顶
Said, to the rooftops!
来吧
Come on!
来吧  唱起来
Come on, let's go!
站起来
Rise up
受到压迫  你得站起来
When you're living on your knees, you rise up
告诉兄弟  他得站起来
Tell your brother that he's gotta rise up
告诉姐妹  她得站起来
Tell your sister that she's gotta rise up
这些殖民地何时才能站起来
When are these colonies gonna rise up?
站起来
Rise up!
我时常想象死亡  熟悉得如同回忆
I imagine death so much it feels more like a memory
我的死期何时降临
When is it gonna get me?
在睡梦中  还是被人夺命
In my sleep? Seven feet ahead of me?
如果我能预见死亡  是该逃跑  还是认命
If I see it comin' do I run, or do I let it be?
死亡是不是就像没有旋律的鼓点
Is it like a beat without a melody?
从没想过我能活过二十岁
See, I never thought I'd live past 20
家乡不少人只能活到十几
Where I come from some get half as many
人生何必匆匆
Ask anybody why we livin' fast
让我们把酒言欢
And we laugh, reach for a flask
把握当下且共从容
We have to make this moment last
便已足够
That's plenty
收回这句
Scratch that
这不是一时冲动
This is not a moment
而是一场运动
It's the movement
聚集有理想有抱负的兄弟
Where all the hungriest brothers with something to prove went
面对敌人
Foes oppose us
我们毅然挺立
We take an honest stand
我们就如摩西
We roll like Moses
夺回应许之地
Claimin' our promised land
如果我们赢得独立
And if we win our independence?
如何保证后裔世世代代自由
Is that a guarantee of freedom for our descendants?
亦或我们洒下的鲜血
Or will the blood we shed
只会带来无尽的复仇
Begin an endless cycle of vengeance
以及死亡与暴力
And death with no defendants?
我知道街头运动让人热血沸腾
I know the action in the street is excitin'
但在流血斗争的间隙
But Jesus, between all the bleedin' and fightin'
我一直坚持阅读写作
I've been readin' and writin'
我们必须理清财务问题
We need to handle our financial situation
我们是联邦国家吗
Are we a nation of states?
我们的国情如何
What's the state of our nation?
我不再耐心等待蹉跎
I'm past patiently waitin'
我斗志昂扬勇往前行
I'm passionately smashin' every expectation
每一步都是破旧立新
Every action's an act of creation
敢于笑对死亡和悲哀
I'm laughin' in the face of casualties and sorrow
人生第一次谋划未来
For the first time, I'm thinkin' past tomorrow
我绝不放过良机
And I am not throwing away my shot
I am not throwing away my shot
我正如我的国家
Hey, yo, I'm just like my country
年轻  好斗  迫切
I'm young, scrappy and hungry
我绝不放过良机
And I'm not throwing away my shot
我们将会崛起  抓住良机
We gonna rise up! Time to take a shot
我们将会崛起  崛起
We're gonna rise up, rise up
是时候抓住良机
It's time to take a shot!
崛起  崛起
Rise up, rise up
是时候抓住良机
It's time to take a shot!
崛起
Rise up
是时候抓住良机
It's time to take a shot!
崛起
Rise up
是时候抓住良机  良机  良机
It's time to take a shot! Shot! Shot!
是时候抓住良机
It's time to take a shot!
抓住良机
Time to take a shot!
我绝不会放过
And I am not throwin' away my
绝不会放过良机
Not throwin' away my shot!
让他们听听
Let 'em hear ya!
来啊
Come on.
最后一杯  先生们
One last round, gents.
也许有生之年  我见不到辉煌
I may not live to see our glory
但我欣然加入战斗
But I will gladly join the fight
当后辈讲述我们的故事
And when our children tell our story
今夜的故事必将代代流传
They'll tell the story of tonight
我们再来一杯
Let's have another round tonight.
Let's have another round tonight
我们再来一杯
举杯敬自由
Raise a glass to freedom
自由的信念永远无法被剥夺
Something they can never take away
无论他们怎么说
No matter what they tell you
举杯敬我们四人
Raise a glass to the four of us
我们前赴后继
Tomorrow there'll be more of us
讲述今夜的故事
Telling the story of tonight
今夜的故事必将代代流传
They'll tell the story of tonight
举杯敬自由
Raise a glass to freedom
自由的信念永远无法被剥夺
Something they can never take away
无论他们怎么说
No matter what they tell you
我们再来一杯
Let's have another round tonight
举杯敬我们四人
Raise a glass to the four of us
我们前赴后继
Tomorrow there'll be more of us
讲述今夜的故事
Telling the story of tonight
我们再来一杯
Let's have another round tonight
今夜的故事必将代代流传
They'll tell the story of tonight
举杯敬自由
Raise a glass to freedom
今夜的故事必将代代流传
They'll tell the story of tonight
举杯敬自由
Raise a glass to freedom
今夜的故事必将代代流传
They'll tell the story of tonight
代代流传
Tell the story of tonight
有钱人们最爱不过
There's nothing rich folks love more
到市中心感受穷人窘迫
Than going downtown and slummin' it with the poor
他们停下马车东张西望
They pull up in their carriages and gawk
盯着学生  看他们高谈阔论
At the students in the common just to watch them talk
以菲利普·斯凯勒为例
Take Philip Schuyler
他富得流油
The man is loaded
但他不知道
But little does he know
他的女儿们  佩吉  安洁莉卡  伊莱莎
That his daughters Peggy, Angelica, Eliza
偷偷溜进城  只为看小伙子们
Sneak into the city just to watch all the guys at--
干活  干活
Work, work
安洁莉卡
Angelica
干活  干活
Work, work
伊莱莎
Eliza
和佩吉
And Peggy
干活  干活
Work, work
斯凯勒姐妹
The Schuyler sisters
安洁莉卡
Angelica
佩吉
Peggy
伊莱莎
Eliza
干活
Work
爸爸说日落前必须回家
Daddy said to be home by sundown
爸爸不需要知道
Daddy doesn't need to know
爸爸说不要去闹市区
Daddy said not to go downtown
就像我说的  你想走就走
Like I said, you're free to go
但看看如今世事
But look around, look around
革命的火焰已在纽约燃起
The revolution's happening in New York
纽约
New York
安洁莉卡  干活
Angelica, work
爸爸想去参加战争已够疯狂
It's bad enough Daddy wants to go to war
有人在广场呐喊
People shouting in the square
我们的海岸将暴力横行已够疯狂
It's bad enough there'll be violence on our shore
新思想在传播着
New ideas in the air
看看如今世事
Look around, look around
安洁莉卡  我们是要寻找什么
Angelica, remind me what we're looking for
她在寻找我
She's lookin' for me!
伊莱莎  我想找个有才干的人
Eliza, I'm lookin' for a mind at work
干活  干活
Work, work
我想找个有才干的人
I'm lookin' for a mind at work
干活  干活
Work, work
我想找个有才干的人
I'm lookin' for a mind at work
干活  干活
Work, work
干活
Work
城里的夏日无与伦比
There's nothin' like summer in the city
有人行色匆匆  有人月貌花容
Someone in a rush next to someone lookin' pretty
不好意思  小姐  恕我无礼
Excuse me, miss, I know it's not funny
奢华的香水  透露出你父亲家财万贯
But your perfume smells like your daddy's got money
你一身华服  为何在城里徘徊
Why you slummin' in the city in your fancy heels?
是否需要流浪儿启迪你的思想
You searchin' for an urchin who can give you ideals?
伯尔  你真叫我恶心
Burr, you disgust me
所以你们议论过我
So you've discussed me
我就像信托基金  宝贝
I'm a trust fund, baby
你完全可以信任
You can trust me
我看过汤玛斯·潘恩所著的《常识》
I've been reading "Common Sense" by Thomas Paine
革命初期发行
阐明殖民地不该继续受英国统治的理由
因此男人说我激进疯狂
So men say that I'm intense or I'm insane
你想要革命  我想要启示
You want a revolution? I wanna revelation!
好好听着我的宣言
So listen to my declaration
"我们认为真理不言而喻
"We hold these truths to be self-evident
出自杰斐逊所著的《独立宣言》
人人生而平等"
That all men are created equal"
等我见到托马斯·杰斐逊
And when I meet Thomas Jefferson
我要迫使他下次包含女人
I'mma compel him to include women in the sequel
干活
Work
看看如今世事
Look around, look around
此刻我们活着是多么幸运
At how lucky we are to be alive right now
看看如今世事
Look around, look around
此刻我们活着是多么幸运
At how lucky we are to be alive right now
曼哈顿正在书写历史
History is happening in Manhattan
我们恰巧身处世界上最伟大的城市
And we just happen to be in the greatest city in the world
世界上最伟大的城市
be in the greatest city in the world
我看过汤玛斯·潘恩所著的《常识》
'Cause I've been reading "Common Sense" By Thomas Paine
看看如今世事
Look around, look around
革命的火焰已在纽约燃起
The revolution's happening in New York
因此男人说我激进疯狂
So men say that I'm intense or I'm insane
你想要革命  我想要启示
You want a revolution? I wanna revelation!
看看如今世事
Look around, look around
革命的火焰已在纽约燃起
The revolution's happening in New York
好好听着我的宣言
So listen to my declaration
"我们认为真理不言而喻
"We hold these truths to be self-evident
看看如今世事
Look around, look around
此刻我们活着是多么幸运
At how lucky we are to be alive right now
人人生而平等"
that all men are created equal"
看看如今世事
Look around, look around
此刻我们活着是多么幸运
At how lucky we are to be alive right now
曼哈顿正在书写历史
History is happening in Manhattan
我们恰巧身处世界上最伟大的城市
And we just happen to be in the greatest city in the world
世界上最伟大的城市
In the greatest city in the world
干活  干活
Work, work
安洁莉卡
Angelica
干活  干活
Work, work
伊莱莎
Eliza
和佩吉
And Peggy
干活  干活
Work, work
斯凯勒姐妹
The Schuyler sisters
干活  干活
Work, work
我们想找个有才干的人
We're looking for a mind at work
干活  干活  干活
Work, work, work, work
最伟大的城市
In the greatest city
世界上最伟大的城市
In the greatest city in the world
听好了  听好了
Hear ye, hear ye!
我叫萨缪尔·西伯里  容我呈现
My name is Samuel Seabury, and I present
《关于大陆国会的自由想法》
"Free Thoughts on the Proceedings of the Continental Congress."
别理会叫嚣革命的乌合之众
Heed not the rabble who scream revolution
他们根本不在乎你们的利益
They have not your interests at heart
天呐  快去骂他个体无完肤
Oh, my God, tear this dude apart
混乱和流血并不是解决办法
Chaos and bloodshed are not a solution
别被他们带入歧途
Don't let them lead you astray
此国会无法代表我
This Congress does not speak for me
别打断他
Let him be.
他们这是引火自焚
They're playing a dangerous game
祈祷国王宽恕你们
I pray the king shows you his mercy
真为你们感到羞耻
For shame
他想要
Yo, he'd have you all unravel
别理会
Heed not the rabble
你们听到叫喊就瓦解
at the sound of screams
叫嚣革命的乌合之众
Who scream revolution
但是革命即将到来
But the revolution is comin'
他们根本不在乎你们的利益
They have not your interests at heart
底层的人民一定会获胜
The have-nots are gonna win this
听你说话  忍笑好难
It's hard to listen to you with a straight face
混乱和流血
Chaos and bloodshed
早已缠上我们
Already haunt us
你还是闭嘴吧
Honestly you shouldn't even talk
并不是解决办法
Are not a solution
别被他们带入歧途
Don't let them lead you astray
那波士顿倾茶呢
And what about Boston?
瞧瞧我们的损失
Look at the cost and all that we've lost
你还敢提国会
And you talk about Congress
此国会无法代表我
This Congress does not speak for me
我的狗都比你能言善辩
My dog speaks more eloquently than thee
他们这是引火自焚
They're playing a dangerous game
奇怪的是  你和狗都一样浑身生癣
But, strangely your mange is the same
祈祷国王宽恕你们
I pray the king shows you his mercy
他在新泽西吗
Is he in Jersey?
真为你们感到羞耻
For shame
为了革命
For the revolution
真为你们感到羞耻
For shame
为了革命
For the revolution
别理会
Heed--
你再敢重复
If you repeat yourself again
我就
I'm gonna--
叫喊
Scream--
说真的  看着我  别看那个
Honestly, look at me Please, don't read
不在乎你们的利益
Not your interests at--
别转调  又不跟我辩论
Don't modulate the key then not debate with me
凭什么让大洋对岸的小岛规定茶叶的价格
Why should a tiny island across the sea regulate the price of tea?
亚历山大  别这样
Alexander, please!
伯尔  我宁愿引起不和  也不要优柔寡断
Burr, I'd rather be divisive than indecisive
少和稀泥
Drop the niceties
肃静
Silence!
国王有令传来
A message from the king!
你说
You say
不愿继续付出  爱的代价
The price of my love's not a price that you're willing to pay
泪洒茶汤
You cry in your tea
看我经过  将茶叶都倒进海里
which you hurled in the sea when you see me go by
你哭什么
Why so sad?
要记住你走时  我们约法三章
Remember we made an arrangement when you went away
现在  你让我龙颜大怒
Now you're making me mad
记住  尽管我们渐行渐远
Remember, despite our estrangement
我依旧是你男人
I'm your man
你早晚会回来
You'll be back
很快就会明白
Soon you'll see
你将记起你属于我
You'll remember you belong to me
你早晚会回来
You'll be back
时间将会证明
Time will tell
你将想起  我曾待你不薄
You'll remember that I served you well
沧海桑田  王朝兴替
Oceans rise, empires fall
我们携手走过一切
We have seen each other through it all
最后关头  若你逼我出手
And when push comes to shove
我将派遣武装大军
I will send a fully armed battalion
让你记起我的爱
To remind you of my love
你说爱已消逝
You say our love is draining
无以为继
And you can't go on
等我离去  你将终日抱怨
You'll be the one complaining when I am gone
不许转换话题
And, no, don't change the subject
你是我最爱的子民
'Cause you're my favorite subject
我温柔顺从的子民
My sweet, submissive subject
我忠实的皇家子民
My loyal, royal subject
永远都是
Forever and ever
永永远远  世世代代
And ever and ever and ever
一如既往  你早晚会回来
You'll be back like before
我将战斗到底  取得胜利
I will fight the fight and win the war
为了你的爱  为了你的称颂
For your love, for your praise
我将爱你爱到垂死之际
And I'll love you till my dying days
等你离去  我将勃然大怒
When you're gone, I'll go mad
所以别丢弃我们的感情
So don't throw away this thing we had
最后关头  若你逼我出手
'Cause when push comes to shove
我将杀光你的亲朋
I will kill your friends and family
让你记起我的爱
To remind you of my love
都给我唱
Everybody!
英国司令何奥  率军远渡重洋
British Admiral Howe's got troops on the water
三万两千大军  驻扎在纽约港
32,000 troops in New York Harbor
等他们包围我们的军队
When they surround our troops
他们包围我们的军队  他们包围我们的军队
They surround our troops. They surround our troops
昔日加勒比的孩子企盼一场战争
As a kid in the Caribbean I wished for a war
贫穷如我  只有这一条路出人头地
I knew that I was poor, I knew it was the only way to rise up
想被世人铭记
If they tell my story
要么光荣战死沙场
I am either gonna die on the battlefield in glory
要么出人头地
Or rise up
我们要捍卫这片土地  但只有一人
We will fight for this land but there's only one man
有资格下令
who can give us a command
让我们起义
So we can rise up
只有一条路  起义  出人头地
Understand, it's the only way to rise up, rise up
他来了
Here he comes
将军驾到
Here comes the general
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
将军驾到
Here comes the general!
你们期待已久的这一刻
The moment you've been waiting for
将军驾到
Here comes the general
弗农山的骄傲
The pride of Mount Vernon
将军驾到
Here comes the general
乔治·华盛顿
George Washington
我们武器不够
We are outgunned
什么
What?
兵力不足
Outmanned
什么
What?
寡不敌众  部署落后
Outnumbered, out-planned
我们要全力以赴
We gotta make an all-out stand
我需要一位左膀右臂
Hey, yo I'm gonna need a right-hand man
听着
Check it
我可否坦诚一秒  哪怕千分一秒也好
Can I be real a second? For just a millisecond?
卸下防备  吐露心声  哪怕一秒
Let down my guard and tell the people how I feel a second?
我是现代少将的典范
Now, I'm the model of a modern major general
受人尊崇的弗吉尼亚老兵
The venerated Virginian veteran
部下争先恐后  把我捧上神坛
whose men are all lining up to put me up on a pedestal
他们给亲戚的信里
writing letters to relatives
都夸赞我的风采和口才
embellishing my elegance and eloquence
但你们视而不见  那赤裸裸的事实
But the elephant is in the room, the truth is in your face
你们听到英军炮声隆隆
When you hear the British cannons go...
胜利的希望不断消逝
Any hope of success is fleeting
我的手下不停撤退
How can I keep leading
那我还怎么领导
when the people I'm leading keep retreating?
我们止住伤亡  英军包围布鲁克林
We put a stop to the bleeding as the British take Brooklyn
马吃车  但看啊
Knight takes rook, but look
我们武器不够
We are outgunned
什么
What?
兵力不足
Outmanned
什么
What?
寡不敌众  部署落后
Outnumbered, out-planned
我们要全力以赴
We gotta make an all-out stand
我需要一位左膀右臂
Hey, yo I'm gonna need a right-hand man
来了
Incoming!
排炮阵地被轰击  清点损失伤亡
They're battering down the Battery, check the damages
我们要阻止他们  灭灭他们的风头
We gotta stop 'em and rob 'em of their advantages
上帝赐我们毅力  我们要坚定立场
Let's take a stand with the stamina God has granted us
汉密尔顿绝不弃船而逃
Hamilton won't abandon ship
我们去偷敌人的火炮
Yo, let's steal their cannons
炮声隆隆  血肉横飞
Goes the cannon, watch the blood and the shit spray
炮声隆隆  我们弃守基普斯湾
Goes the cannon, we're abandoning Kip's Bay
又一艘船被击沉
And there's another ship, and...
曼哈顿岛南端失守
We just lost the southern tip, and...
我们得迅速撤到哈莱姆
We gotta run to Harlem quick
再败一场我们都遭不住
We can't afford another slip
备好武器鞍马  我决定分散兵力
Guns and horses, giddyap. I decide to divvy up my forces
英军攻城略地  我军人心惶惶
They're skittish as the British cut the city up
差一点就要放弃  千夫所指
This close to giving up, facing mad scrutiny
面对叛变的众人  我高喊
I scream in the face of this mass mutiny
难道我要跟这群人保卫美利坚
Are these the men with which I am to defend America?
我们夜奔行军  远远望着曼哈顿
We ride at midnight, Manhattan in the distance
我分身乏术  各位
I cannot be everywhere at once, people,
我急需辅助
I'm in dire need of assistance
-尊敬的长官  -你是谁
- Your Excellency, sir. - Who are you?
亚隆·伯尔  长官  可以说说我的想法吗
Aaron Burr, sir. Permission to state my case?
你请便
As you were.
长官  我曾是蒙哥马利将军麾下的上尉
Sir, I was a captain under General Montgomery
但他在魁北克颈部中弹
Until he caught a bullet in the neck in Quebec
总而言之  我觉得自己能帮上忙
Well, in summary, I think that I could be of some assistance
我敬佩您一直从远处向英军开火
I admire how you keep firing on the British from a distance
我有几个问题  想提几个建议
I have some questions, a couple of suggestions
我们要抗击  而不是西逃
on how to fight instead of fleeing west
-请讲  -那么
- Yes? - Well--
长官  您要见我
Your Excellency, you wanted to see me?
汉密尔顿  进来  你认识伯尔吗
Hamilton, come in. Have you met Burr?
-认识  长官  我们总碰到  -我们总碰到
- Yes, sir. We keep meeting. - We keep meeting.
我刚才说  长官
As I was saying, sir,
我期待您的战略发挥成效
I look forward to seeing your strategy play out.
-伯尔  -长官
- Burr? - Sir?
出去后把门关上
Close the door on your way out.
我做错什么了吗  长官
Have I done something wrong, sir?
正相反
On the contrary
我叫你过来是因为我们的胜算太渺茫
I called you here because our odds are beyond scary
你的大名如雷贯耳
Your reputation precedes you
-但我忍不住发笑  -长官
- But I have to laugh. - Sir?
汉密尔顿  怎么就没人把你招致麾下
Hamilton, how come no one can get you on their staff?
长官
Sir--
别误会我  你是个有名望的年轻人
Don't get me wrong. You're a young man of great renown
我们在市区战斗时你偷了英军的火炮
I know you stole British cannons when we were still downtown
纳瑟内尔·格林和亨利·诺克斯都想将你收入靡下
Nathanael Greene and Henry Knox wanted to hire you
做他们的秘书  我才不愿意
Yeah, to be their secretary. I don't think so.
-你有何不满  -我没有
- Now, why are you upset? - I'm not.
没关系  你想战斗  你迫切立功
It's all right, you wanna fight. You've got a hunger
我年轻时跟你一样
I was just like you when I was younger
满心都是作为烈士赴死的幻想
Head full of fantasies of dying like a martyr?
没错
Yes.
死去反而轻松  年轻人  活着才更艰辛
Dying is easy, young man, living is harder
-为什么要跟我说这些  -我说实话
- Why are you telling me this? - I'm being honest
我手上的资源只有国会许诺的三分之一
I'm working with a third of what our Congress has promised
我们是个快要爆炸的火药桶
We are a powder keg about to explode
我需要你这样的人帮我减轻负担
I need someone like you to lighten the load
你怎么说
So...
我绝不放过良机
I am not throwing away my shot
我正如我的国家
Hey, yo, I'm just like my country
年轻  好斗  迫切
I'm young, scrappy and hungry
我绝不放过良机
I am not throwing away my shot
孩子  我们武器不够  兵力不足
Son, we are outgunned, outmanned
您需要所有的帮助  我有些朋友
You need all the help you can get. I have some friends
劳伦斯  马利根  拉法耶特侯爵  还缺什么
Laurens, Mulligan, Marquis de Lafayette. Okay, what else?
寡不敌众  部署落后
Outnumbered, out-planned
我们需要敌人内部的间谍
We'll need some spies on the inside
找些敷衍了事的英王手下
Some king's men who might let some things slide
我给国会写信申请物资
I'll write to Congress and tell 'em we need supplies
您召集人马  出其不意攻其不备
You rally the guys, master the element of surprise
英雄不问出处  我来整合情报
I'll rise above my station, organize your information
直到我们建立新的国家  长官
Till we rise to the occasion of our new nation, sir!
将军驾到
Here comes the general
出人头地
Rise up
什么
What?
将军驾到
Here comes the general
起立致敬
Rise up
什么
What?
将军驾到
Here comes the general
起义
Rise up
什么
What?
将军驾到
Here comes the general
什么
What?
还有他的左膀右臂
And his right-hand man!
私生之子  孤苦之人  荡妇之子
How does a bastard, orphan, son of a whore
竟能风生水起  成为现象级人物
go on and on, grow into more of a phenomenon?
眼睁睁看着这个讨人厌的傲慢大嘴巴
Watch this obnoxious arrogant loudmouth bother
当上国父的得力助手
Be seated at the right hand of the father
华盛顿当场任用汉密尔顿
Washington hires Hamilton right on sight
但汉密尔顿依然想上战场  不想做文职
But Hamilton still wants to fight, not write
汉密尔顿的笔杆子本事确实出色
Now, Hamilton's skill with a quill is undeniable
要说我们都有什么共同点
But what do we have in common?
我们都是姑娘们的好伴侣
We're reliable with the...
姑娘们
Ladies
娇嫩欲滴任人采撷
There are so many to deflower
姑娘们
Ladies
看啊  变凤凰的捷径
Looks! Proximity to power
姑娘们
Ladies
她们让他欣喜  也迷了他的眼
Oh, they delighted and distracted him
玛莎·华盛顿给捡回的公猫取了他的名字
Martha Washington named her feral tomcat after him
确有其事
That's true.
1780年  冬日舞会
1780, a winter's ball
人人艳羡斯凯勒三姐妹
And the Schuyler sisters are the envy of all
能娶到其中一位  你就发了  孩子
Yo, if you could marry a sister, you're rich, son
问题是能不能娶到  还是娶哪一位  伯尔
Is it a question of "If", Burr, or which one?
我愿意  我愿意  我愿意
I do, I do, I do, I do
你让我情难自禁
Boy, you got me helpless
望着你的双眼  深邃无尽
Look into your eyes and the sky's the limit
我情难自禁
I'm helpless
为你沉沦  淹没在脉脉眼波中
Down for the count and I'm drownin' in 'em
我从来不是爱抢风头的人
I have never been the type to try and grab the spotlight
那个热情的夜晚  我们跟叛军一同狂欢
We were at a revel with some rebels on a hot night
笑话我姐姐  因为她让全场意乱情迷
Laughin' at my sister as she's dazzling the room
然后你走进来  我的心突然狂跳
Then you walked in and my heart went boom
想从舞厅的一侧吸引你的目光
Tryin' to catch your eye from the side of the ballroom
大家都在跳舞  乐队放开音量演奏
Everybody's dancin' and the band's top volume
踏着节奏  我们享受美酒佳肴
Grind to the rhythm as we wine and dine
我抓住我姐姐悄声道  "这人我要了"
Grab my sister and whisper "Yo, this one's mine"
我姐姐穿过舞厅走向你
My sister made her way across the room to you
我好紧张  想着"她要干什么"
And I got nervous, thinking, "What's she gonna do?"
她抓住你的胳膊  我想"我完蛋了"
She grabs you by the arm, I'm thinkin', "I'm through"
你看向我  我突然情难自禁
Then you look back at me and suddenly I'm helpless
你动人的双眼
Oh, look at those eyes, oh
望着你的双眼  深邃无尽
Look into your eyes and the sky's the limit
我情难自禁  我知道
I'm helpless, I know
为你沉沦  淹没在脉脉眼波中
Down for the count and I'm drownin' in 'em
情难自禁
Helpless
我一见钟情
I'm so into you
望着你的双眼  深邃无尽
Look into your eyes and the sky's the limit
我一见钟情
I am so into you
情难自禁
Helpless
我知道我为你沉沦  淹没在脉脉眼波中
I know I'm down for the count and I'm drownin' in 'em
-你要带我去哪里  -我要改变你的人生
- Where are you taking me? - I'm about to change your life.
那恭敬不如从命
Then by all means, lead the way.
伊丽莎白·斯凯勒  幸会
Elizabeth Schuyler. It's a pleasure to meet you.
-斯凯勒  -我妹妹
- Schuyler? - My sister.
感谢你浴血奋战
Thank you for all your service.
倘若我们相识的代价就是开战
If it takes fighting a war for us to meet,
那这仗打得也值了
it will have been worth it.
我不打扰你们了
I'll leave you to it.
一周后  我每晚挑灯写信
One week later, I'm writin' a letter nightly
每收到你的一封信  我都觉得生活更加美好
Now my life gets better every letter that you write me
笑话我姐姐  因为她想做你的女眷
Laughin' at my sister 'cause she wants to form a harem
我说说而已  你真爱我的话  就跟我分享他
I'm just sayin', if you really loved me, you would share him
两周后  在客厅里我焦虑不安
Two weeks later in the living room stressin'
你向我父亲寻求祝福  但他板着脸
My father, stone-faced while you're asking for his blessin'
你们吃吃喝喝  我急得要死
I'm dying inside as you wine and dine
强忍泪水
And I'm tryin' not to cry
因为只要你想  无所不能
'cause there's nothing that your mind can't do
我父亲穿过房间来到你面前
My father makes his way across the room to you
一瞬间我慌了神  想着"我们完蛋了"
I panic for a second, thinking, "We're through"
但他握了握你的手  说"要忠贞不渝"
But then he shakes your hand and says, "Be true"
你转身笑着望向我  而我
And you turn back to me, smiling and I'm...
情难自禁
Helpless
望着你的双眼  深邃无尽
Look into your eyes and the sky's the limit
我情难自禁
I'm helpless
为你沉沦  淹没在脉脉眼波中
Down for the count and I'm drownin' in 'em
情难自禁
Helpless
他属于我
He's mine
他是我的意中人
That boy is mine
望着你的双眼  深邃无尽
Look into your eyes and the sky's the limit
我情难自禁
I'm helpless
情难自禁
Helpless
为你沉沦  淹没在脉脉眼波中
Down for the count and I'm drownin' in 'em
伊莱莎  我身无一文
Eliza, I don't have a dollar to my name
名下无地  麾下无兵  默默无闻
An acre of land, a troop to command, a dollop of fame
只有道义气节  百折不挠
All I have's my honor, a tolerance for pain
成绩优异  聪明绝顶
A couple of college credits and my top-notch brain
说来疯狂  你们一家唤醒我的另一面
Insane, your family brings out a different side of me
佩吉向我吐露真言  安洁莉卡想占有我
Peggy confides in me, Angelica tried to take a bite of me
不要担心  我对你的爱毋庸置疑
No stress, my love for you is never in doubt
我们可以去哈莱姆定居  开启新生活
We'll get a little place in Harlem and we'll figure it out
我自小孤苦伶仃
I've been livin' without a family since I was a child
父亲离家  母亲离世
My father left, my mother died
我就是个野孩子
I grew up buck-wild
但我永远都无法忘却我母亲的脸庞
But I'll never forget my mother's face, that was real
只要我还活着  伊莱莎  我对天发誓
And long as I'm alive, Eliza Swear to God
你绝不会受那些苦
You'll never feel that
情难自禁
Helpless
我愿意  我愿意
I do, I do, I do, I do
伊莱莎
Eliza
情难自禁
Helpless
我愿意  我愿意
I do, I do, I do, I do
我从未如此
I've never felt so...
情难自禁
Helpless
为你沉沦  淹没在脉脉眼波中
Down for the count And I'm drownin' in 'em
我已为你沉沦  我
I'm down for the count, I'm...
我的人生将一片光明  因为有了伊莱莎
Yo, my life is gonna be fine, 'Cause Eliza's in it
情难自禁
Helpless
望着你的双眼  深邃无尽
I look into your eyes and the sky's the limit
情难自禁
Helpless
为你沉沦  淹没在脉脉眼波中
Down for the count and I'm drownin' in 'em
人到纽约  改头换面
In New York, you can be a new man
情难自禁
Helpless
好了好了  这才对嘛
All right, all right. That's what I'm talking about!
各位  有请伴娘
Now, everyone, give it up for the maid of honor,
安洁莉卡·斯凯勒
Angelica Schuyler!
举杯敬新郎
A toast to the groom
敬新郎  敬新郎  敬新郎
To the groom, to the groom, to the groom
敬新娘
To the bride
敬新娘  敬新娘
To the bride, to the bride
作为你的姐姐
From your sister
安洁莉卡
Angelica
我会一直陪伴在你左右
Who's always by your side
在你左右
By your side
敬你们喜结连理
To your union
敬美利坚  敬革命
To the Union, to the revolution
愿你们自强不息
And the hope that you provide
自强不息  自强不息
You provide, you provide
愿你们永远
And may you always
永远
Always
心满意足
Be satisfied
时光倒流
Rewind
情难自禁
Helpless
深邃无尽
Skies
淹没
Drowning
时光倒流
Rewind
回忆起那晚  我可能
I remember that night, I just might
时光倒流
Rewind
回忆起那晚  回忆起...
I remember that night-- I remember that--
回忆起那晚
I remember that night
我可能会为此后悔一辈子
I just might regret that night for the rest of my days
还记得那群年轻气盛的军人
I remember those soldier boys
急不可耐地想要讨我们欢心
tripping over themselves to win our praise
还记得那如梦似幻的烛光
I remember that dreamlike candlelight
如此虚无缥缈
Like a dream that you can't quite place
但是亚历山大
But, Alexander
我永远忘不了与你初见的那一天
I'll never forget the first time I saw your face
我就此不同
I have never been the same
你那睿智的双眼  精瘦的体格
Intelligent eyes in a hunger-pang frame
你向我问声好  我便忘却自己姓名
And when you said "Hi," I forgot my dang name
挑拨起我心中的火焰  燃遍全身
Set my heart aflame, every part aflame
这不是场游戏
This is not a game
在我看来  你好像从未满足过
You strike me as a woman who has never been satisfied
我不懂你在说什么  你逾越了
I'm sure I don't know what you mean, you forget yourself
你和我一样  我就从不满足
You're like me, I'm never satisfied
是吗
Is that right?
我从未满足
I have never been satisfied
我叫安洁莉卡·斯凯勒
My name is Angelica Schuyler
亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Alexander Hamilton
你家世如何
Where's your family from?
那不重要  志向千千万  我才刚开始
Unimportant, there's a million things I haven't done
不过你等着瞧  你等着瞧
But just you wait, just you wait...
难道这就是斗智斗勇
So, so, so, so this is what it feels like to match wits
棋逢对手的感觉  这里头肯定有诈
With someone at your level, what the hell is the catch?
这感觉如同重见光明
It's the feeling of freedom of seeing the light
如同富兰克林风筝迎闪电
It's Ben Franklin with a key and a kite
你看见了吧
You see it, right?
三两分钟的交谈
The conversation lasted two minutes, maybe three minutes
我们便情投意合
Everything we said in total agreement
就像是一场梦  一支舞
It's a dream and it's a bit of a dance
故作姿态  摆明立场
A bit of a posture, it's a bit of a stance
他虽风流  但我也愿意给个机会
He's a bit of a flirt, but I'mma give it a chance
询问起家况  他竟那样答复
I asked about his family, did you see his answer?
他局促不安  眼神躲闪
His hands started fidgeting, he looked askance
他身无分文  摸爬滚打
He's penniless, he's flying by the seat of his pants
他是那样一表人才
Handsome, boy, does he know it
零星的胡须  稚气仍未脱
Peach fuzz, and he can't even grow it
我想带他远远逃离这里
I wanna take him far away from this place
但转身看见我的妹妹  她已经
Then I turn and see my sister's face and she is...
情难自禁
Helpless
我知道她已经
And I know she is...
情难自禁
Helpless
她的眼神已经
And her eyes are just...
情难自禁
Helpless
与此同时我意识到三大基本真理
And I realize three fundamental truths at the exact same time
-你要带我去哪里  -我要改变你的人生
- Where are you taking me? - I'm about to change your life.
那恭敬不如从命
Then by all means, lead the way.
第一
Number one
我只用嫁给一个富人家
I'm a girl in a world in which my only job is to marry rich
事实上她父亲有数个儿子
但是家父不曾育有儿子
My father has no sons,
所以得靠我来攀附权贵
so I'm the one who has to social climb for one
因为我是最聪明的长女
'Cause I'm the oldest and the wittiest
而纽约城满是流言蜚语
And the gossip in New York City is insidious
虽然亚历山大身无分文
And Alexander is penniless
我的爱意也丝毫不会减
Ha, that doesn't mean I want him any less
伊丽莎白·斯凯勒  幸会
Elizabeth Schuyler. It's a pleasure to meet you.
-斯凯勒  -我妹妹
- Schuyler? - My sister.
第二
Number two
他追求我  只因我是斯凯勒家千金
He's after me, 'Cause I'm a Schuyler sister
这能提升他的地位
That elevates his status
抛开这点也太天真  正是因此
I'd have to be naive to set that aside, maybe that is why
我才给他介绍伊莱莎  如今已是他的新娘
I introduced him to Eliza, now that's his bride
干得好  安洁莉卡  他说得对
Nice going, Angelica, he was right
你永远不会满足
You will never be satisfied
感谢你浴血奋战
Thank you for all your service.
倘若我们相识的代价就是开战
If it takes fighting a war for us to meet,
那这仗打得也值了
it will have been worth it.
我不打扰你们了
I'll leave you to it.
第三
Number three
我对我妹妹了如指掌
I know my sister Like I know my own mind
再也不会有人像她那般纯真善良
You will never find anyone as trusting or as kind
若我对她诉衷肠  她会默默成全
If I tell her that I love him, she'd be silently resigned
他将属于我  而她会故作轻松
He'd be mine, she would say, "I'm fine"
但那都是假装
She'd be lying
每个夜晚  我都会想起亚历山大的双眸
But when I fantasize at night, it's Alexander's eyes
我会幻想  若我没有断然评判他
As I romanticize what might have been
现在又会如何
If I hadn't sized him up so quickly
至少亲爱的伊莱莎是他的妻子
At least my dear Eliza's his wife
至少我还能见到他那双眸
At least I keep his eyes in my life
敬新郎
To the groom
敬新郎  敬新郎  敬新郎
To the groom, to the groom
敬新娘
To the bride
敬新娘  敬新娘
To the bride, to the bride
作为你的姐姐
From your sister
安洁莉卡  安洁莉卡
Angelica, Angelica
我会一直伴你左右
Who's always by your side
伴你左右
By your side
敬你们喜结连理
To your union
敬美利坚  敬革命
To the Union, to the revolution
愿你们自强不息
And the hope that you provide
自强不息  自强不息
You provide, you provide
愿你们永远
May you always...
永远
Always
心满意足
Be satisfied
我知道
And I know...
她会是幸福的新娘
She'll be happy as his bride
我也知道
And I know
他永远都不会满足
He will never be satisfied
我永远也不会满足
I will never be satisfied
也许有生之年  我见不到辉煌
I may not live to see our glory
但我至少见过大小奇迹
But I've seen wonders great and small
I've seen wonders great and small
倘若野猫都能成婚
'Cause if the tomcat can get married
亚历山大都能成婚
If Alexander can get married
说明我们都有机会
There's hope for our ass, after all
举杯敬自由
Raise a glass to freedom
你以后可不再是自由身
Something you will never see again
不管她如何交代你
No matter what she tells you
我们再来一杯
Let's have another round tonight
举杯敬我们四人
Raise a glass to the four of us
敬刚刚脱贫的我们
To the newly not-poor of us
我们会讲述今夜的故事
We'll tell the story of tonight
我们再来一杯
Let's have another round
-这不是亚隆·伯尔吗  -先生
- Well, if it isn't Aaron Burr - Sir.
-没想到你真的会来  -肯定的
- I didn't think that you would make it - To be sure
-伯尔  -我是来道喜的
- Burr. - I came to say congratulations
-来一段  伯尔  -大家伙儿都在呢
- Spit a verse, Burr - I see the whole gang is here
你最差劲了  伯尔
You are the worst, Burr
别理他们  祝贺你  陆军中校
Ignore them Congrats to you, Lieutenant Colonel
我真希望和你一样领军
I wish I had your command
而不是保管乔治的日记
Instead of manning George's journal
-你才不想  -我真想
- No, you don't - Yes, I do
放明智一点
Now, be sensible
我听说你成了不可或缺的大人物
From what I hear, you've made yourself indispensable
我倒是听说
Well, well, I heard
你金屋藏娇  伯尔
You've got a special someone on the side, Burr
是吗
Is that so?
你在隐瞒什么  伯尔
What are you tryin' to hide, Burr?
-我该走了  -不  该走的是他们
- I should go. - No, these guys should go.
-别来烦我们  -别这样
- Leave us alone. - Man.
没关系  伯尔
It's all right, Burr
今晚把那姑娘带来多好  伯尔
I wish you'd brought this girl with you tonight, Burr
你这么说真好  但恐怕我做的是不法勾当
You're very kind, but I'm afraid it's unlawful, sir.
-什么意思  -她结婚了
- What do you mean? - She's married.
-懂了  -她嫁给了一位英国军官
- I see. - She's married to a British officer.
该死
Oh, shit.
再次恭喜你  亚历山大
Congrats again, Alexander
多微笑
Smile more
我们战场上见
See you on the other side of the war
我永远理解不了你
I will never understand you
如果你爱这个女人  就去追求她
If you love this woman, go get her
你在等什么
What are you waiting for?
我们战场上见
See you on the other side of the war
I'll see you on the other side of the war
西奥多西娅与第一任丈夫育有三女两子
在他因伤去世后嫁给伯尔  育有一女
西奥多西娅每天给我写信
Theodosia writes me a letter every day
当她丈夫不在时  我替她暖床
I'm keeping her bed warm while her husband is away
他在乔治亚替英国而战
He's on the British side in Georgia
他想让殖民地井井有条
He's trying to keep the colonies in line
他可以留着整个乔治亚
Well, he can keep all of Georgia
但西奥多西娅  她是我的
Theodosia, she's mine
爱情不分罪人圣徒
Love doesn't discriminate between the sinners and the saints
它不断索取  我们仍付出真心
It takes and it takes and it takes and we keep loving anyway
我们哭笑  我们粉碎
We laugh and we cry and we break
我们犯错
And we make our mistakes
许多男人屡试未果
And if there's a reason I'm by her side
假若她有青睐我的理由
When so many have tried
那我愿意等待
Then I'm willing to wait for it
我愿意等待
I'm willing to wait for it
乔纳森·爱德华是大觉醒运动的领袖
被视为美国基督精神之父
他的布道《落在愤怒之神手中的罪人》享有盛誉
曾任普林斯顿校长
我外公是个作风严厉的牧师
My grandfather was a fire and brimstone preacher
但也有布道和赞美诗传授不了的知识
But there are things that the homilies and hymns won't teach ya
我母亲是个天才
My mother was a genius
天才
Genius
我父亲备受尊重
My father commanded respect
尊重
Respect
他们去世时未留下只言片语
When they died they left no instructions
只有需保护的名声
Just a legacy to protect
死亡不分罪人圣徒
Death doesn't discriminate between the sinners and the saints
它不断索取  我们仍努力拼搏
It takes and it takes and it takes and we keep living anyway
我们起落  我们粉碎
We rise and we fall and we break
我们犯错
And we make our mistakes
所有爱过我的人逝去
And if there's a reason I'm still alive
假若我有活着的理由
When everyone who loves me has died
我愿意等待
I'm willing to wait for it
等待
Wait for it
我愿意等待
I'm willing to wait for it
等待
Wait for it
等待  等待  等待
Wait for it, wait for it, wait for it
我只能掌握自己的人生
I am the one thing in life I can control
等待  等待  等待  等待
Wait for it, wait for it wait for it, wait for it
我无法效仿  独一无二
I am inimitable, I am an original
等待  等待  等待  等待
Wait for it, wait for it wait for it, wait for it
我不落后  也不迟到
I'm not falling behind or running late
等待  等待  等待  等待
Wait for it, wait for it wait for it, wait for it
我不坐以待毙  而是伏击等待
I'm not standing still I am lying in wait
汉密尔顿前方漫漫长路
Hamilton faces an endless uphill climb
他要证明自我
He has something to prove
他失无可失
He has nothing to lose
汉密尔顿步履不停
Hamilton's pace is relentless
他不虚度光阴
He wastes no time
他是何种感受呢
What is it like in his shoes?
汉密尔顿从不犹豫
Hamilton doesn't hesitate
他无拘无束
He exhibits no restraint
他不断索取
He takes and he takes and he takes
却一直取胜
And he keeps winning anyway
改变游戏
Changes the game
加大赌注
Plays and he raises the stakes
幸存的人寥寥无几
And if there's a reason he seems to thrive
假若他有所向睥睨的理由
When so few survive
那我愿意等待
Then, goddamn it, I'm willing to wait for it
等待  等待
Wait for it, wait for it
我愿意等待
I'm willing to wait for it
生活不分罪人圣徒
Life doesn't discriminate between the sinners and the saints
它不断索取
It takes and it takes and it takes
我们仍努力拼搏
And we keep living anyway
我们起
We rise
我们起落  我们粉碎
We rise and we fall and we break
我们犯错
And we make our mistakes
我们落
We fall
数不清的人逝去
And if there's a reason I'm still alive
假若我有活着的理由
When so many have died
那我愿意
Then I'm willing to--
等待
Wait for it
活下去
Stay alive
我从没见过将军如此沮丧
I have never seen the general so despondent
我接手掌管他的所有通信
I have taken over writing all his correspondence
国会来信  "乔治  向英军进攻"
Congress writes "George, attack the British forces"
我回复  "我们已开始杀马果腹"
I shoot back "We have resorted to eating our horses"
本地商户拒绝为我们提供装备和协助
Local merchants deny us equipment, assistance
他们只收英国货币
They only take British money
唱一首六便士之歌吧
So sing a song of sixpence
-救兵不来了  -但长官
- Cavalry's not coming. - But, sir--
亚历克斯  我们想赢只有一个办法
Alex, listen. There's only one way for us to win this.
激起民愤
Provoke outrage, outright.
没错
That's right.
别开火  夜里突袭
Don't engage, strike by night
坚守阵地  直到对方撤退
Remain relentless till their troops take flight
让英军无法辩解战争的代价
Make it impossible to justify the cost of the fight
-跑得快  -跑得快
- Outrun - Outrun
-抗得久  -抗得久
- Outlast - Outlast
快进攻  速撤退
Hit 'em quick, get out fast
坚持活到这场恐怖秀结束
Stay alive until this horror show is past
我们将要祭奠许多同胞
We're gonna fly a lot of flags half-mast
举杯
Raise a glass
我回到纽约  继续做学徒
I go back to New York and my apprenticeship
我请求法国援助  希望法国能派船只
I ask for French aid, I pray that France has sent a ship
我继续跟着汉密尔顿
I stay at work with Hamilton
撰写反奴隶制的文章
We write essays against slavery
每天都是对我们友情和勇气的考验
And every day's a test of our camaraderie and bravery
于是我们切断补给线
So we cut supply lines
偷窃走私货
We steal contraband
选择各自的战争
We pick and choose our battles
和自己的立场
And places to take a stand
每一天  "长官  请允许我领军"
And every day "Sir, entrust me with a command"
-而每一天  -不行
- And every day - No.
他都立刻否决我
He dismisses me out of hand
活下去
Stay alive
取而代之他却提拔
Instead of me he promotes
查尔斯·李
Charles Lee
让他成为副指挥
Makes him second-in-command
我是将军了
I'm a general. Whee!
没错  我不会选择他
Yeah, he's not the choice I would have gone with
孟莫斯之役他落荒而逃
He shits the bed at the Battle of Monmouth
-各位  进攻  -撤退
- Everyone, attack - Retreat
-进攻  -撤退
- Attack - Retreat
你在干什么  李  赶紧好好指挥
What are you doing, Lee? Get back on your feet
-对方人数众多  -不好意思  这不合你心意
- There's so many of them - I'm sorry, is this not your speed?
-汉密尔顿  -准备好了
- Hamilton! - Ready, sir!
-让拉法耶特指挥  -遵命
- Have Lafayette take the lead. - Yes, sir!
千名士兵死于38度高温
A thousand soldiers die In 100-degree heat
我们勉强打成平手  逃过一败
As we snatch a stalemate from the jaws of defeat
查尔斯·李成了弃子  身败名裂
Charles Lee was left behind without a pot to piss in
只要人愿听  他便开口讲
He started saying this to anybody who would listen
不能放任华盛顿一意孤行
Washington cannot be left alone to his devices
优柔寡断  危机不断
Indecisive, from crisis to crisis
他对革命最大的贡献
The best thing he could do for the revolution
就是回弗农山种烟草
Is turn and go back to planting tobacco in Mount Vernon
什么也别做
Don't do a thing
历史会证明他是错的
History will prove him wrong
-但长官  -我们还有仗要打
- But, sir-- - We have a war to fight
继续前进
Let's move along
李出言挑衅
Strong words from Lee
必须向他挑战
Someone ought to hold him to it
我不能违抗命令
I can't disobey direct orders
那我来
Then I'll do it.
亚历山大  你是我最好的朋友
Alexander, you're the closest friend I've got.
劳伦斯  不要放过良机射偏
Laurens, do not throw away your shot.
一  二  三  四  五  六  七  八  九
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine
这是决斗十诫
It's the ten duel commandments
第一
Number one
挑战目的在于满意
The challenge, demand satisfaction
如果对方道歉  则无需决斗
If they apologize no need for further action
第二
Number two
倘若不道歉  找个朋友做你的副手
If they don't, grab a friend, hat's your second
你的副官
Your lieutenant
替你做最后的清算
When there's reckoning to be reckoned
第三
Number three
双方的副手面对面
Have your seconds meet face-to-face
进行和平谈判
Negotiate a peace
或定下时间和地点
Or negotiate a time and place
常见的情况
This is commonplace
尤其在新兵之间
Especially between recruits
多数纷争  不战而消
Most disputes die, and no one shoots
第四
Number four
如果无法达成一致
If they don't reach a peace
那没关系
That's all right
拿把手枪
Time to get some pistols
让医生待命
And a doctor on site
提前付钱
You pay him in advance
礼貌待人
You treat him with civility
让他转身
You have him turn around
方便事后推诿
So he can have deniability
第五
Five
对决要在太阳升起前
Duel before the sun is in the sky
找个困兽之地赴死
Pick a place to die where it's high and dry
第六
Number six
给至亲留张字条
Leave a note for your next of kin
告诉他们你去哪拼命
Tell 'em where you been
祈祷天堂或地狱对你敞开大门
Pray that hell or heaven lets you in
第七
Seven
忏悔罪过
Confess your sins
等你见到对手
Ready for the moment of adrenaline
准备好肾上腺素飙升
When you finally face your opponent
第八
Number eight
最后的协商机会
Your last chance to negotiate
派出副手  看是否能澄清误会
Send in your seconds see if they can set the record straight
-亚历山大  -亚隆·伯尔  先生
- Alexander - Aaron Burr, sir
我们能否同意对决即愚蠢又幼稚
Can we agree that duels are dumb and immature?
当然  但你的人要为言行付出代价  伯尔
Sure, but your man has to answer for his words, Burr
用他的生命吗  我们都明白这太荒唐  先生
With his life? We both know that's absurd, sir
等一下  有多少人的死
Hang on, how many men died
是因为李缺乏经验  行事鲁莽
because Lee was inexperienced and ruinous?
好吧  看来非决斗不可
Okay, so we're doing this
第九
Number nine!
盯着对方的眼睛  别瞄高了
Look 'em in the eye, aim no higher
鼓起全部勇气
Summon all the courage you require
然后数数
Then count
一  二  三  四  五  六  七  八  九
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine
-几步  -十步
- Number! - Ten paces!
开枪
Fire!
李  你投降吗
Lee, do you yield?
你击中他的侧身  他投降
You shot him in the side Yes, he yields
-我满意了  -我们得清理现场
- I'm satisfied! - Yo, we gotta clear the field
走吧  我们赢了
Go, we won
将军驾到
Here comes the general!
-有好戏看了  -这是什么情况
- This should be fun - What is the meaning of this?
伯尔先生  给将军叫医生
Mr. Burr, get a medic for the general
遵命
Yes, sir.
李  你我永远看不对眼
Lee, you will never agree with me
但相信我
But believe me
这些年轻人无法代表我
These young men don't speak for me
-您辛苦了  -我们走
- Thank you for your service - Let's ride
-汉密尔顿  -长官
- Hamilton. - Sir!
我要跟你谈谈
Meet me inside.
跟你谈谈  跟你谈谈
Meet him inside, meet him inside
跟你谈谈  跟你谈谈  跟你谈谈
Meet him inside, meet him, meet him inside
-孩子  -别叫我孩子
- Son-- - Don't call me son.
即便没有内讧这仗已很难打
This war is hard enough without infighting.
李向你挑衅
Lee called you out.
-我们就向他挑战  -你这样解决不了问题
- We called his bluff. - You solve nothing.
你激怒了我们南方的盟友
You aggravate our allies to the south.
你说得没错
You're absolutely right.
约翰就该一枪打烂他的嘴
John should have shot him in the mouth.
让他彻底闭嘴
That would've shut him up.
-孩子  -我不是你的孩子
- Son-- - I'm not your son--
注意你的态度
Watch your tone.
我不是需要人保护的弱者
I am not a maiden in need of defending,
-我能处理好  -查尔斯·李  托马斯·康威
- I am grown! - Charles Lee, Thomas Conway,
这些人四处败坏你的名声
these men take your name and they rake it through the mud.
我已经历过许多非议  我能承受
My name's been through a lot I can take it.
但我没有你的名声
Well, I don't have your name,
没有你的头衔  没有你的领地
I don't have your titles, I don't have your land.
-但如果你...  -不行
- But if you-- - No.
如果你给我一个营  让我带领这些人
If you gave me command of a battalion, a group of men to lead,
我就能战后一举成名
I could fly above my station after the war.
你也可能丧命  你必须活着
Or you could die, and we need you alive.
我不怕死
I am more than willing to die!
你妻子需要你活着  孩子  我需要你活着
Your wife needs you alive, son. I need you alive!
你再叫我一次孩子试试
Call me son one more time!
回家吧  亚历山大
Go home, Alexander.
这是司令下达的命令
That's an order from your commander.
长官
Sir--
回家
Go home!
看看如今世事
Look around, look around
此刻我们活着是多么幸运
At how lucky we are to be alive right now
仔细看看  仔细看看
Look around, look around
你知道多久了
How long have you known?
-大概一个月  -伊莱莎
- A month or so - Eliza
你早该告诉我
You should have told me
我一个月前写信给将军
I wrote to the general a month ago
-不  -我求他准你解甲归田
- No - I begged him to send you home
你早该告诉我
You should have told me
我不后悔
I'm not sorry
-我知道你会战斗至最终胜利  -战争还未结束
- I knew you'd fight Until the war was won - The war's not done
但你应该有机会见见自己的儿子
But you deserve a chance to meet your son
看这世事  看这世事
Look around, look around
此刻我们活着是多么幸运
At how lucky we are to be alive right now
你甘愿做穷人的妻子吗
Will you relish being a poor man's wife?
他无法为你带来富足的生活
Unable to provide for your life
我甘愿做你的妻子
I relish being your wife
看这世事  看这世事
Look around, look around
看看你如今的成就
Look at where you are
想想你曾一无所有
Look at where you started
你还活着就是个奇迹
The fact that you're alive is a miracle
只要你活着便已足够
Just stay alive, that would be enough
如果这个孩子
And if this child
有一分你的笑容
Shares a fraction of your smile
有一分你的抱负
Or a fragment of your mind
对这世界来说
Look out, world
那便已足够
That would be enough
我不会假装理解
I don't pretend to know
你所面对的困难
The challenges you're facing
你在头脑中反复
The worlds you keep erasing
推翻重建的世界
And creating in your mind
但我无所畏惧
But I'm not afraid
我了解我的丈夫
I know who I married
只要你最终能回家
So long as you come home at the end of the day
那便已足够
That would be enough
我们不需要万世流芳
We don't need a legacy
也不需要家财万贯
We don't need money
若我能为你带来安宁
If I could grant you peace of mind
若你能对我敞开心扉
If you could let me inside your heart
让我成为这故事的一部分吧
Oh, let me be a part of the narrative
在未来人们会写下的史书中
In the story they will write someday
让此刻成为第一个篇章
Let this moment be the first chapter
只要你愿意留下
Where you decide to stay
我便心满意足了
And I could be enough
对我们来说就已足够
And we could be enough
那便已足够
That would be enough
衣衫褴褛  自发组织  乌合之众
How does a ragtag volunteer army in need of a shower
竟想打败一位世界霸主
Somehow defeat a global superpower?
我们如何从进退两难转败为胜
How do we emerge victorious from the quagmire?
让贝特西·罗斯的星条旗高高飘扬
Leave the battlefield waving Betsy Ross's flag higher?
被美国公众广泛认作国旗的首位制作者
其实我们有个秘密武器
Yo, turns out we have a secret weapon
一位你们熟知且喜爱的移民  他不惧挺身而出
An immigrant you know and love who's unafraid to step in
他不断地把大不列颠的走狗耍得团团转
He's constantly confusing, confounding the British henchmen
大家欢迎美利坚最喜爱的法国战士
Everyone give it up for America's favorite fighting Frenchman
拉法耶特
Lafayette
我手执缰绳策马飞奔
I'm takin' this horse by the reins
让这些英国兵血溅三尺
Makin' redcoats redder with bloodstains
拉法耶特
Lafayette
我不会停止  将他们打败  将他们毁灭
And I'm never gonna stop until I make 'em drop or burn 'em up
将他们挫骨扬灰  我是
And scatter their remains, I'm--
拉法耶特
Lafayette
打得他们屁滚尿流落荒而逃怒火中烧  我是
Watch me engagin' 'em, escapin' 'em, enragin' 'em, I'm--
拉法耶特
Lafayette
我去法国筹钱
I go to France for more funds
拉法耶特
Lafayette
带回来更多的武器和船只
I come back with more guns and ships
让战局扭转
And so the balance shifts
我们跟罗尚博会师  联合我们的兵力
We rendezvous with Rochambeau, consolidate their gifts
我们能在约克镇结束这场战争
We can end this war at Yorktown
让他们败于海上
Cut them off at sea
但要想成功我们仍需另外一个人
But for this to succeed, there is someone else we need
我知道
I know
汉密尔顿
Hamilton
长官  他熟悉战壕作战
Sir, he knows what to do in a trench
机敏过人且法语流利
Ingenuitive and fluent in French, I mean
汉密尔顿
Hamilton
你总归要用到他的才智
You're gonna have to use him eventually
让他场外观战有何意义
What's he gonna do on the bench? I mean
汉密尔顿
Hamilton
没人比得上他的应变能力
No one has more resilience or matches
也没人能媲美我的天才战术
My practical tactical brilliance
汉密尔顿
Hamilton
你想夺回自己的土地吗
You want to fight for your land back?
汉密尔顿
Hamilton
我需要找回我的左膀右臂
I need my right-hand man back
汉密尔顿
Hamilton
找回你的左膀右臂
Get your right-hand man back
汉密尔顿
Hamilton
你明白需要找回你的左膀右臂
You know you gotta get your right-hand man back
汉密尔顿
Hamilton
你得给他写封信  越快越好
Gotta put some thought into the letter but the sooner the better
汉密尔顿
Hamilton
找回你的左膀右臂
To get your right-hand man back
亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Alexander Hamilton
军队正在战场上等你
Troops are waiting in the field for you
如果你此刻加入
If you join us right now
我们可以携手扭转战局
Together we can turn the tide
亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Oh, Alexander Hamilton
士兵们都在等你号令
I have soldiers that will yield for you
如果我们打好这场战役
If we manage to get this right
他们将在破晓时投降
They'll surrender by early light
世界从此不同
The world will never be the same
亚历山大
Alexander
我第一次领军杀敌时
I was younger than you are now
比你现在还要年轻
When I was given my first command
我领手下冲进一场屠杀
I led my men straight into a massacre
我亲眼目睹他们的死亡
I witnessed their deaths firsthand
我曾犯下无数过错
I made every mistake
心中愧疚与日俱增
And felt the shame rise in me
时至今日我深夜难眠
And even now I lie awake
深知我所做的一切  自有历史评判
Knowing history has its eyes on me
我所做的一切  自有历史评判
History has its eyes on me
年轻时的我梦想荣耀
Let me tell you what I wish I'd known
多希望那时我就懂得
When I was young and dreamed of glory
你无法左右
You have no control
谁生  谁死  谁讲述你的故事
Who lives? Who dies? Who tells your story?
我知道我们能获得胜利
I know that we can win
我知道你怀有远大抱负
I know that greatness lies in you
但你记住  从此刻起
But remember, from here on in
你所做的一切  自有历史评判
History has its eyes on you
约克镇战役
The Battle of Yorktown.
1781年
1781.
-汉密尔顿先生  -拉法耶特先生
- Monsieur Hamilton - Monsieur Lafayette
-终于来到战场  你的归属  -完全没在怕的
- In command, where you belong - How you say? No sweat
我们终于来到战场  这一路可不容易
We're finally on the field, we've had quite a run
我们是移民
Immigrants
成事还得靠我们
We get the job done
-要是战胜你有什么打算  -我要回法国
- So, what happens if we win? - I go back to France
如果有机会  我要解放我的同胞
I bring freedom to my people if I am given the chance
那时我们将全力支持
We'll be with you when you do
去吧  带领你的士兵
Go, lead your men
-江湖再见  -后会有期  上啊
- See you on the other side - Till we meet again, let's go!
我绝不放过良机
I am not throwing away my shot!
我正如我的国家  年轻  好斗  迫切
Hey, yo, I'm just like my country I'm young, scrappy and hungry
我绝不放过良机
And I'm not throwing away my shot
I am not throwing away my shot
看世界天翻地覆
Till the world turns upside down
我时常想象死亡  熟悉得如同回忆
I've imagined death so much it feels more like a memory
这就是我的死期  站着等敌人袭来
This is where it gets me, on my feet, the enemy ahead of me
若人生终于此处  至少有朋友知己
If this is the end of me, at least I have a friend with me
手握武器  带领士兵  并肩作战
Weapon in my hand, a command, and my men with me
然后我想起伊莱莎在家等我
Then I remember my Eliza's expecting me
不仅如此  伊莱莎即将临盆
Not only that, my Eliza's expecting
我们必须战斗  我们必须胜利
We gotta go, gotta get the job done
建立新的国家  迎接我的儿子
Gotta start a new nation, gotta meet my son
-把子弹从枪中卸掉  -什么
- Take the bullets out your gun - What?
-子弹卸掉  -什么
- The bullets out your gun - What?
暗中前行
We move undercover
我们整齐划一
And we move as one
趁着夜色偷袭  成败在此一举
Through the night, we have one shot to live another day
别让走火暴露行迹
We cannot let a stray gunshot give us away
近身搏斗  抓住时机  坚定不移
We will fight up close, seize the moment and stay in it
不成功  便成仁
It's either that or meet the business end of a bayonet
暗号是  "罗尚博"
The code word is, "Rochambeau"
音似"向前冲"
-明白吗  -罗尚博
- Dig me? - Rochambeau
命令已经下达  伙计们向前冲
You have your orders now, go, men, go
就此揭开  独立大业
And so the American experiment begins
至交兄弟  征战八方
With my friends all scattered to the winds
南卡罗莱纳  劳伦斯写出英勇的新篇章
Laurens is in South Carolina, redefining bravery
只有奴隶不再  自由才会到来
We'll never be free Until we end slavery
当英军鱼溃鸟散
When we finally drive the British away
拉法耶特早已经
Lafayette is there waiting
守在切萨皮克湾
In Chesapeake Bay
我们何以确信  此计必将凯旋
How did we know that this plan would work?
我方内应  深入敌军  是的没错
We had a spy on the inside, that's right
赫丘利·穆里根
Hercules Mulligan!
裁缝监视英国政府
A tailor spying on the British government
我量体裁衣  我搜集信息
I take their measurements, information
我瞒天过海
And then I smuggle it up
为革命盟友通风报信
To my brother's revolutionary covenant
携手"自由之子"  有种就来
I'm running with the Sons of Liberty and I am loving it!
反抗英国统治的激进秘密组织
曾发动波士顿茶党事件  故俗称波士顿茶党
招惹无赖  就是自讨苦吃
See, that's what happens when you up against the ruffians
身陷困境  谁来收烂摊子
We in the shit now, somebody's gotta shovel it
赫丘利·穆里根  早已声名远扬
Hercules Mulligan, I need no introduction
一次次被击倒  又一次次矗立
When you knock me down I get the fuck back up again!
向左  向右  稳住
Left! Right! Hold!
前进
Go!
无所畏惧  所向披靡
What? What? What?
七日征战
After a week of fighting
红衣军官  走上城墙
A young man in a red coat stands on a parapet
挥起白绢  我们放下枪炮
We lower our guns as he frantically waves a white handkerchief
战争就这样终结
And just like that, it's over.
我们照顾伤员  我们缅怀死者
We tend to our wounded, we count our dead.
黑人士兵  白人士兵  一同思忖
Black and white soldiers wonder alike
自由是否触手可及
if this really means freedom.
为时尚早
Not yet.
我们谈判投降条件
We negotiate the terms of surrender.
我看见乔治·华盛顿笑容满面
I see George Washington smile.
我们押解英军出城
We escort their men out of Yorktown.
敌人所剩无几  溃不成军
They stagger home single file.
民众走上街头  万人空巷
Tens of thousands of people flood the streets.
人们欢呼雀跃  教堂钟声齐天
There are screams and church bells ringing,
敌人落荒而逃
and as our fallen foes retreat,
人们把酒言欢
I hear the drinking song they're singing.
世界天翻地覆
The world turned upside down
天翻地覆  天翻地覆
Down, down, down, down
为美利坚自由而战  为法兰西自由而战
Freedom for America! Freedom for France!
天翻地覆  天翻地覆
Down, down, down
建立新的国家  迎接我的儿子
Gotta start a new nation, gotta meet my son
天翻地覆  天翻地覆
Down, down, down
我们胜利了  我们胜利了
We won! We won!
世界天翻地覆
The world turned upside down
他们说
They say
不愿替我承担  战争代价
The price of my war's not a price that they're willing to pay
愚蠢至极
Insane
你勾结法国人
You cheat with the French
法国和西班牙  同时对我开战
Now I'm fighting with France and with Spain
我好忧伤
I'm so blue
我以为你走时  我们约法三章
I thought that we made an arrangement when you went away
你要唯我是瞻
You were mine to subdue
就算现在  我们渐行渐远
Well, even despite our estrangement
我依旧要问你
I've got a small query for you
下一步何处去  你已获得自由
What comes next? You've been freed
可你是否留意  掌权何其不易
Do you know how hard it is to lead?
如今你要自立
You're on your own
你真棒棒
Awesome, wow
可你是否明晰  今后何去何从
Do you have a clue what happens now?
沧海桑田  王朝兴替
Oceans rise, empires fall
手握大权  进退两难
It's much harder when it's all your call
大洋彼岸  孤掌难鸣
All alone across the sea
待到民怨沸腾日
When your people say they hate you
可别向我来乞求
Don't come crawling back to me
如今你要自立
You're on your own
宝贝西奥多莎  我该如何表达
Dear Theodosia, what to say to you
你的双眸如我  名字随你妈妈
You have my eyes you have your mother's name
当你呱呱坠地
When you came into the world, you cried
我已满怀情愫
And it broke my heart
时刻为你守护
I'm dedicating every day to you
我从不曾想过  眷恋家庭生活
Domestic life was never quite my style
当你笑容洋溢
When you smile
我已无力抗拒
You knock me out, I fall apart
我曾自诩伶俐
And I thought I was so smart
你和这个国家  一同慢慢长大
You will come of age with our young nation
我们要为你浴血奋战
We'll bleed and fight for you
我们要为你披襟斩棘
We'll make it right for you
若是我们能夯实根基
If we lay a strong enough foundation
我们将把它传承于你
We'll pass it on to you
我们给你整个天地  有朝一日
We'll give the world to you and you'll blow us all away
你将震撼环宇
Someday, someday
Yeah, you'll blow us all away
有朝一日  有朝一日
Someday, someday
菲利普啊  你的笑颜  让我沦陷
Oh, Philip, when you smile I am undone
我的儿子
My son
看着你啊  我的儿子
Look at my son
我的骄傲  无言以表
Pride is not the word I'm looking for
我的内心  情绪万千
There is so much more inside me now
菲利普啊  你让朝阳黯然失色
Oh, Philip, you outshine the morning sun
我的儿子
My son
当你笑容洋溢
When you smile
我已无力抗拒
I fall apart
我曾自诩伶俐
And I thought I was so smart
自幼父亲缺席
My father wasn't around
我一定要  伴你左右
Swear that I'll be around for you
伴你左右
I'll be around for you
我会不惜一切
I'll do whatever it takes
我会不断试错
I'll make a million mistakes
为你撑起  世界祥和
I'll make the world safe and sound for you
你和这个国家  一同慢慢长大
You'll come of age with our young nation
我们要为你浴血奋战
We'll bleed and fight for you
我们要为你披襟斩棘
We'll make it right for you
若是我们能夯实根基
If we lay a strong enough foundation
我们将把它传承于你
We'll pass it on to you
我们给你整个天地
We'll give the world to you
你将震撼环宇
And you'll blow us all away
有朝一日  有朝一日
Someday, someday
你将震撼环宇
Yeah, you'll blow us all away
有朝一日  有朝一日
Someday, someday
也许有生之年  我见不到辉煌
I may not live to see our glory
亚历山大  有你的信
Alexander, there's a letter for you.
是约翰·劳伦斯  我等会再去读
It's from John Laurens. I'll read it later.
但我欣然加入战斗
But I will gladly join the fight
不是  是他父亲
No. It's from his father.
他父亲
His father?
当后辈讲述我们的故事
And when our children tell our story
可以读给我听吗
Will you read it for me?
今夜的故事必将代代流传
They'll tell the story of tonight
"周四  27日
"On Tuesday the 27th,
我的儿子在南卡罗莱纳
my son was killed in a gunfight
与撤退途中的英军交火丧生
against British troops retreating from South Carolina.
战争已经结束
The war was already over.
你也知道  约翰梦想
As you know, John dreamed
解放招募三千黑奴
of emancipating and recruiting 3,000 men
创建首支黑人军团
for the first all-black military regiment.
随着他逝去的  还有他的自由之梦"
His dream of freedom for these men dies with him."
我们前赴后继
Tomorrow there'll be more of us
亚历山大  你没事吧
Alexander, are you all right?
革命尚未成功
I have so much work to do.
战争过后  我回到纽约
After the war I went back to New York
A-After the war I went back to New York
我完成学业  我从事法律工作
I finished up my studies and I practiced law
我从事法律工作  伯尔在隔壁工作
I practiced law, Burr worked next door
尽管我们同时起家
Even though we started at the very same time
亚历山大迅速崭露头角
Alexander Hamilton began to climb
他又是如何  登上顶峰
How to account for his rise to the top?
这个人啊  从不歇息
Man, the man is nonstop
各位陪审成员  我实在太好奇  请允许我提问
Gentlemen of the jury, I'm curious, bear with me
你们是否知道  我们正在创造历史
Are you aware that we're making history?
这是建国以来  首起谋杀案件
This is the first murder trial of our brand-new nation
审议基于自由
The liberty behind deliberation
从不歇息
Nonstop
我要拨开疑团
I intend to prove beyond
携助理律师  证明给你们看
a shadow of a doubt with my assistant counsel--
是合作律师  汉密尔顿  你坐下
Co-counsel. Hamilton, sit down
我们的当事人李维·维克斯是无辜的
Our client, Levi Weeks, is innocent
传唤首位证人
Call your first witness
你无须再多言
That was all you had to say
好吧  还有一事
Okay, one more thing--
你凭什么认定  就你聪明绝顶
Why do you assume you're the smartest in the room?
这种态度  早晚万劫不复
Soon that attitude may be your doom
为何笔耕不辍  仿佛时日无多
Why do you write like you're running out of time?
日夜笔耕不辍  仿佛时日无多
Write day and night like you're running out of time
每天口诛笔伐  仿佛时日无多
Every day you fight like you're running out of time
与此同时  你斗争不止
Keep on fighting, in the meantime...
从不歇息
Nonstop
腐败堕落  我们早已司空见惯
Corruption's such an old song that we can sing along in harmony
最恶劣处  非奥巴尼莫属
And nowhere is it stronger than in Albany
这块殖民地的经济愈发失控
This colony's economy's increasingly stalling
这正是政府需要我的原因
And honestly, that's why public service seems to be calling me
他从不歇息
He's just nonstop
我从事法律工作  我还完善法律
I practiced the law, I practically perfected it
每次目睹世间不公  我都将其一一纠正
I've seen injustice in the world and I've corrected it
是时候建立中央民主制
Now for a strong central democracy
若不成功  我要效仿苏格拉底
If not, then I'll be Socrates
语言巨石  攻击平庸之辈
Throwing verbal rocks at these mediocrities
汉密尔顿  出席制宪会议
Hamilton, at the Constitutional Convention
我被选中  参加制宪会议
I was chosen for the Constitutional Convention
作为纽约青年代表
There as a New York junior delegate
我要说的话有些刺耳
Now, what I'm going to say may sound indelicate...
他在会上提出自己对政体的提议
Goes and proposes his own form of government
什么
What?
对新政体他有自己的计划
His own plan for a new form of government
什么
What?
六小时唇枪舌战  议员们神思倦怠
Talks for six hours, the convention is listless
小伙有头脑
Bright young man
这人谁啊
Yo, who the eff is this?
为何你总直抒己见
Why do you always say what you believe?
每句宣言都令你成为众矢之的
Every proclamation guarantees free ammunition for your enemies
为何笔耕不辍  仿佛不合时宜
Why do you write like it's going out of style?
日夜笔耕不辍  仿佛不合时宜
Write day and night like it's going out of style
每天口诛笔伐  仿佛不合时宜
Every day you fight like it's going out of style
你少掺和
Do what you do
亚历山大
Alexander
亚隆·伯尔  先生
Aaron Burr, sir.
已是午夜了
Well, it's the middle of the night.
我们能谈谈吗  先生
Can we confer, sir?
-是法务问题吗  -是的  这对我来说很重要
- Is this a legal matter? - Yes, and it's important to me.
-你有什么需要  -伯尔  你做律师比我在行
- What do you need? - Burr, you're a better lawyer than me.
然后呢
Okay.
我知道我说话又多又糙
I know I talk too much, I'm abrasive
你在法庭上十分出色  语言干练而有说服力
You're incredible in court. You're succinct, persuasive
我的当事人需要有力的辩护  你能搞定
My client needs a strong defense. You're the solution
-你的当事人是谁  -新美国《宪法》
- Uh, who's your client? - The new US Constitution.
-不行  -听我说完
- No. - Hear me out.
没门
No way.
一系列匿名发表的文章
A series of essays anonymously published
向公众声援宪法
defending the document to the public
-没人会读的  -我认为有
- No one'll read it. - I disagree.
如果失败了呢
And if it fails?
伯尔  因此才需要它
Burr, that's why we need it.
-《宪法》一塌糊涂  -因此才需要修订
- The Constitution's a mess. - So it needs amendments.
-充满矛盾  -独立也是
- It's full of contradictions. - So is independence.
-万事开头难  -不  不行
- We have to start somewhere. - No. No way.
-你在犯错误  -晚安
- You're making a mistake. - Good night.
你在等什么  你还犹豫什么
What are you waiting for? What do you stall for?
-什么  -我们打赢了战争  图什么
- What? - We won the war. What was it all for?
-你支持新《宪法》吗  -当然
- Do you support this Constitution? - Of course.
-那就为它辩护  -万一你下错注呢
- Then defend it. - What if you're backing the wrong horse?
伯尔  我们一起学习  奋战  杀敌
Burr, we studied and we fought and we killed
只为如今我们所建国家的信念
for the notion of a nation we now get to build
哪怕此生仅有一次  你也应骄傲地表态
For once in your life, take a stand with pride
我不明白你怎能袖手旁观
I don't understand how you stand to the side
我要将所有计划深藏不露
I will keep all my plans close to my chest
等待  等待  等待
Wait for it, wait for it, wait...
我要作壁上观  见机行事
I'll wait here and see which way the wind will blow
我要静观其变
I'm taking my time
看着国家诞生
watching the afterbirth of a nation
看着矛盾激化
watching the tension grow
我将向伦敦起航
I am sailing off to London
与一个慷慨多金的人同往
I'm accompanied by someone who always pays
我找到一位富有的丈夫
I have found a wealthy husband
事实上安洁莉卡与汉密尔顿相遇时已嫁为人妇
她与丈夫育有三女五子
他将令我余生衣食无忧
who will keep me in comfort for all my days
他不算有趣
He is not a lot of fun
但论口才  谁也不可与你同日而语
but there's no one who can match you for turn of phrase
-我的亚历山大  -安洁莉卡
- My Alexander - Angelica
别忘记写信
Don't forget to write
看看你如今的成就
Look at where you are
想想你曾一无所有
Look at where you started
你还活着就是个奇迹
The fact that you're alive is a miracle
只要你活着便已足够
Just stay alive, that would be enough
若你能分给妻子一点时间
And if your wife could share a fraction of your time
若我能为你带来安宁
If I could grant you peace of mind
那便足够吗
Would that be enough?
亚历山大与詹姆斯·麦迪逊和约翰·杰伊联手
Alexander joins forces with James Madison and John Jay
写下一系列文章
to write a series of essays
为新美国《宪法》辩护
defending the new United States Constitution
题为《联邦论》
entitled "The Federalist Papers"
计划是共写25篇文章
The plan was to write a total of 25 essays,
由三人平分工作量
the work divided evenly among the three men.
最终  他们在六个月间写出85篇文章
In the end, they wrote 85 essays in the span of six months.
约翰·杰伊写了五篇后病倒
John Jay got sick after writing five.
詹姆斯·麦迪逊写了29篇
James Madison wrote 29.
其余51篇由汉密尔顿所写
Hamilton wrote the other 51!
为何笔耕不辍  仿佛时日无多
How do you write like you're running out of time?
日夜笔耕不辍  仿佛时日无多
Write day and night like you're running out of time
每天口诛笔伐  仿佛时日无多
Every day you fight like you're running out of time
时日无多  是否时日无多
Running out of time? Are you running out of time?
为何笔耕不辍  仿佛没有明天
How do you write like tomorrow won't arrive?
为何笔耕不辍  仿佛命系笔尖
How do you write like you need it to survive?
为何笔耕不辍  时刻争分夺秒
How do you write every second you're alive?
争分夺秒  争分夺秒
Every second you're alive, every second you're alive
他们要我领导
They're asking me to lead
我将尽我所能
I'm doing the best I can
召集所需之人
to get the people that I need
请你担任副手
I'm asking you to be my right-hand man
财政还是国务
Treasury or State?
我明白这是不情之请
I know it's a lot to ask
财政还是国务
Treasury or State?
离开你熟知的世界
To leave behind the world you know
长官  您想让我负责财政部还是国务院
Sir, do you want me to run the Treasury or State Department?
财政部
Treasury.
那走起
Let's go.
亚历山大
Alexander...
我得离开
I have to leave.
亚历山大
Alexander.
看看如今世事
Look around, look around
此刻我们活着是多么幸运
At how lucky we are to be alive right now
情难自禁
Helpless
他们要我领导
They are asking me to lead
看这世事  这还不够吗
Look around, isn't this enough?
他永远不会满足
He will never be satisfied
如何才能满足
What would be enough to be satisfied?
他永远不会满足
He will never be satisfied
满足  满足
Satisfied, satisfied
你所做的一切  自有历史评判
History has its eyes on you
你凭什么认定  就你聪明绝顶
Why do you assume you're the smartest in the room?
这还不够吗
Isn't this enough?
那便足够吗
Will it be enough?
你所做的一切  自有历史评判
History has its eyes on you
为何笔耕不辍  仿佛时日无多
Why do you write like you're running out of time?
为何笔耕不辍
Why do you write like...
你所做的一切  自有历史评判
History has its eyes on you
我绝不放过良机
I am not throwing away my shot
你们等着瞧
Just you wait
我绝不放过良机
I am not throwing away my shot
你们等着瞧
Just you wait
我叫亚历山大·汉密尔顿
I am Alexander Hamilton
汉密尔顿  汉密尔顿
Hamilton, Hamilton
你们等着瞧
Just you wait
我绝不放过良机
I am not throwing away my shot!
幕间休息
一七
Seventeen
一  一  一七
Se-se-seventeen
1789年
私生之子  孤苦之人
How does the bastard, orphan
移民之人  授勋老兵
Immigrant, decorated war vet
竟想通过  债务治国
Unite the colonies through more debt?
斗遍开国元勋  直到无处立足
Fight the other founding fathers till he has to forfeit
从坐拥一切  到一无所有
Have it all, lose it all.
还想接着看
You ready for more yet?
他是财政部长  华盛顿是总统
Treasury secretary, Washington's the president
每一项新措  都开创先河
Every American experiment sets a precedent
别太得意  对手马上就来
Not so fast, someone came along to resist him
跟他对干  促成两党治国
Pissed him off until we had a two-party system
他没登场  你们还没见过
You haven't met him yet, you haven't had the chance
人在法国  大使叱咤风云
'Cause he's been kickin' ass as the ambassador to France
总得回来  维护美国承诺
But someone's gotta keep the American promise
快来见见托马斯  托马斯
You simply must meet Thomas, Thomas!
托马斯·杰斐逊回家了
Thomas Jefferson's coming home!
Thomas Jefferson's coming home
托马斯·杰斐逊回家了
天呐  他在巴黎待了好久
Lord, he's been off in Paris for so long
法国紧随我们革命的步伐
France is following us to revolution
曾经的局面已被打破
There is no more status quo
但太阳照常升起  世界仍在运转
But the sun comes up, and the world still spins
我帮拉法耶特起草了一份宣言
I helped Lafayette draft a declaration
然后我说  "我得走了
Then I said, "I gotta go
得回蒙蒂塞洛"
Gotta be in Monticello"
开展祖国的大业
Now the work at home begins
那么我错过了什么
So what did I miss?
我错过了什么
What did I miss?
弗吉尼亚  亲爱的家乡  我要吻你
Virginia, my home sweet home, I wanna give you a kiss
我在巴黎坐拥各色美女
I've been in Paris meeting lots of different ladies
基本上错过了八十年代末期
I guess I basically missed the late '80s
我游历大千世界  回到这里
I traveled the wide, wide world and came back to this
我桌上有封总统来信
There's a letter on my desk from the president
行李都还没卸下
Haven't even put my bag down yet
萨莉  乖宝贝  替我拆信好吗
Sally, be a lamb, darlin'. Won'tcha open it?
萨莉·海明斯从十几岁时就成为杰佛逊的情妇
系杰佛逊的岳父约翰·威勒斯与黑奴所生
和杰佛逊的妻子玛莎·威勒斯同父异母
与杰佛逊育有至少六个孩子
但这些子嗣直到杰佛逊死后才获得自由
萨莉终生没有脱离奴役
信上说总统正在组建内阁
It says the president's assembling a cabinet
将会任命我为国务卿
And that I am to be the secretary of state
妙极  我已获参议院批准
Great. And that I'm already Senate-approved
我刚到家就要赶往纽约
I just got home and now I'm headed up to New York
赶往纽约  赶往纽约
Headin' to New York! Headin' to New York!
看着起伏的田野
Lookin' at the rolling fields
真不敢相信我们已获自由
I can't believe that we are free
杰斐逊一生中大量蓄奴
准备好面对纽约
Ready to face whatever's
等待着我的一切
awaiting me in NYC
当我踏入纽约  等待我的是谁
But who's waitin' for me when I step in the place?
我的朋友  詹姆斯·麦迪逊
My friend, James Madison
他面红耳赤
Red in the face
握住我的手臂  我问"近来如何"
he grabs my arm and I respond, "What's goin' on?"
托马斯  我们正处于一场斗争
Thomas, we are engaged in a battle
事关国家精神
for our nation's very soul
你能帮我们摆脱泥潭吗
Can you get us out of the mess we're in?
汉密尔顿的新财政方案
Hamilton's new financial plan is nothing less
汉密尔顿意图建立美国中央银行
旨在让联邦政府掌控财政
全然就是政府管制
than government control
我一直单枪匹马为南方抗争
I've been fighting for the South alone
你去哪了
Where have you been?
法国  怎么
France. What?
我们必须赢
We have to win.
我错过了什么
What did I miss?
我回家来就为这个
I've come home to this?
一头扎入政治深渊
Headfirst into a political abyss
一头扎入深渊
Headfirst into the abyss
今天首次参加内阁会议
I have my first cabinet meeting today
我得想想该说什么
I guess I better think of something to say
我已启程  定要弄个水落石出
I'm already on my way. Let's get to the bottom of this
我错过了什么
What did I miss?
杰斐逊先生  欢迎回家
Mr. Jefferson, welcome home
杰斐逊先生  我是亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Mr. Jefferson? Alexander Hamilton
杰斐逊先生  欢迎回家
Mr. Jefferson, welcome home
杰斐逊先生  欢迎回家  先生
Mr. Jefferson, welcome home, sir
你在巴黎
You've been off in Paris
待了好久
For so long!
那么我错过了什么
So what did I miss?
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
你们从世界各地远道而来
you could've been anywhere in the world tonight,
与我们相聚纽约市
but you're here with us in New York City.
准备好参加内阁会议了吗
Are you ready for a cabinet meeting?
本次的议题是
The issue on the table:
汉密尔顿部长的提案
Secretary Hamilton's plan to
承担州债  建立国家银行
assume state debt and establish a national bank.
杰斐逊国务卿  请您发言
Secretary Jefferson, you have the floor, sir.
"生命权  自由权和追求幸福的权利"
"Life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness"
出自《独立宣言》
我们曾为理想战斗  不该退让将就
We fought for these ideals, we shouldn't settle for less
这些智言慧语  有为之士常挂嘴边
These are wise words, enterprising men quote 'em
别故作惊讶  这些都出自我笔下
Don't act surprised, you guys, 'cause I wrote 'em
但汉密尔顿选择疏忽
But Hamilton forgets
他计划让政府承担州债
His plan would have the government assume states' debts
我们打个赌  最后谁受益
Now, place your bets as to who that benefits
正是财政部长  汉密尔顿本人
The very seat of government where Hamilton sits
-不对  -既然是事实  就老实承认
- Not true! - Ooh, if the shoe fits, wear it
纽约欠债  凭什么让弗吉尼亚承担
If New York's in debt, why should Virginia bear it?
我们已无债一身轻
Our debts are paid, I'm afraid
别看南方富足无虞  就给我们加税
Don't tax the South 'cause we got it made in the shade
弗吉尼亚人开垦土地  创造价值
In Virginia, we plant seeds in the ground, we create
你只是想挪用我们的资产
You just wanna move our money around
你这财政计划厚颜无耻
This financial plan is an outrageous demand
还长篇大论  谁都看不懂
And it's too many damn pages for any man to understand
请和我守护这片自由土地
Stand with me in the land of the free
向天祈祷  永远别让汉密尔顿参选
Pray to God we never see Hamilton's candidacy
英国向我们征茶税  我们奋起反抗
Look, when Britain taxed our tea, we got frisky
要是你敢征酒税  想想后果会如何
Imagine what gon' happen when you try to tax our whiskey
谢谢  杰斐逊国务卿
Thank you, Secretary Jefferson.
汉密尔顿部长  请回应
Secretary Hamilton, your response.
托马斯  算你舌灿莲花
Thomas, that was a real nice declaration
欢迎回到现实  我们不是在过家家
Welcome to the present, we're running a real nation
你要加入我们  还是归隐田园
Would you like to join us, or stay mellow
回老家蒙蒂塞洛歌舞升平
Doin' whatever the hell it is you do in Monticello?
如果我们承担债务  联邦将会获得
If we assume the debts, the Union gets
财政刺激  新的信贷额度
A new line of credit, a financial diuretic
你是揣着明白装糊涂
How do you not get it?
只有大胆争先  联邦才会强大
If we're aggressive and competitive, the Union gets a boost
你宁愿一瓢冷水泼下
You'd rather give it a sedative?
奴隶主大谈公民权利
A civics lesson from a slaver
邻居  你无债一身轻  靠的是免费劳力
Hey, neighbor, your debts are paid 'cause you don't pay for labor
"南方人开垦土地  创造价值"
"We plant seeds in the South, we create"
大话不要停  地里是谁耕作的身影
Yeah, keep ranting, we know who's really doing the planting
还有一事  启蒙时代先生
And another thing, Mr. Age of Enlightenment
启蒙时代是指十七至十八世纪
欧洲地区发生的一场知识及文化运动
你都没参战  少跟我说教
Don't lecture me about the war you didn't fight in it
你以为我怕你吗  我们差点死在战壕里
You think I'm frightened of you, man? We almost died in a trench
你却跟法国佬打得火热
While you were off getting high with the French
托马斯·杰斐逊  总统问什么都犹豫不决
Thomas Jefferson, always hesitant with the President
寡言少语  没一个计划能得他首肯
Reticent, there isn't a plan he hasn't jettisoned
麦迪逊  你个疯子  别忘吃药
Madison, you mad as a hatter, son, take your medicine
你们的状态比国家债务还要不堪
Damn, you're in worse shape than the national debt is in
两个百无一用的废物
Sittin' there useless as two shits
转个身  撅起屁股  让我擦擦鞋底
Hey, turn around, bend over, I'll show you where my shoe fits
打断一下
Excuse me.
麦迪逊  杰斐逊  出去走走
Madison, Jefferson, take a walk.
汉密尔顿  你也是
Hamilton, take a walk.
稍事休息  再来开会
We're gonna reconvene after a brief recess.
-汉密尔顿  -长官
- Hamilton. - Sir.
借一步说话
A word.
没人支持你
You don't have the votes
你需要国会批准
You're gonna need congressional approval
但没人支持你
And you don't have the votes
笨嘴拙舌
Such a blunder
我真不明白  自己何必兴师动众
Sometimes it makes me wonder why I even bring the thunder
他何必兴师动众
Why he even brings the thunder
你冷静下来了吗
You wanna pull yourself together?
抱歉  这些弗吉尼亚人就是一丘之貉
I'm sorry. These Virginians are birds of a feather.
年轻人  我也是弗吉尼亚人  说话小心点
Young man, I'm from Virginia, so, watch your mouth.
那就任由南方人挟持国会吗
So we let Congress get held hostage by the South?
-你需要有人支持  -不  我们需要放手一搏
- You need the votes. - No, we need bold strokes.
-这个提案势在必行  -不  你需要说服更多人
- We need this plan. - No, you need to convince more folks.
詹姆斯·麦迪逊不搭理我  根本不可能
Well, James Madison won't talk to me, that's a nonstarter.
赢很轻松  年轻人  治国才更艰辛
Winning was easy, young man, governing's harder.
-他们不肯让步  -你得找出折衷之策
- They're being intransigent. - You have to find a compromise.
他们根本没想法  只是看不上我的
They don't have a plan. They just hate mine!
想办法说服他们
Convince them otherwise.
要是得不到国会批准会如何
And what happens if I don't get congressional approval?
他们应该会要求你下台
I imagine they'll call for your removal.
-长官  -想办法解决  亚历山大
- Sir. - Figure it out, Alexander.
这是总统下达的命令
That's an order from your commander.
一  二  三  四  五  六  七  八  九
Un, deux, trois, quatre, cinq, six, sept, huit, neuf
很好
Good!
一  二  三  四  五  六  七  八  九
Un, deux, trois, quatre, cinq, six, sept, huit, neuf
七  八  九
Sept, huit, neuf
一  二  三  四  五  六  七  八  九
One, two, three, four, five six, seven, eight, nine!
亲爱的安洁莉卡
My dearest, Angelica
出自《麦克白》
麦克白在得知夫人死后的感慨
"明天  明天  又一个明天
"Tomorrow and tomorrow and tomorrow
迈着琐碎的脚步  日复一日走过"
Creeps in this petty pace from day to day"
我想你一定明白
I trust you'll understand
我又引用了一部苏格兰悲剧
The reference to another Scottish tragedy
不必点明出处
Without my having to name the play
他们把我比作麦克白  怀揣愚蠢的野心
They think me Macbeth, ambition is my folly
视我为博学家  眼中钉  肉中刺
I'm a polymath, a pain in the ass, a massive pain
麦迪逊是班戈  杰斐逊是麦克德夫
Madison is Banquo, Jefferson's Macduff
班戈曾是麦克白的战友  后与麦克白决裂被刺杀
麦克白杀害麦克德夫的妻儿  最终被麦克德夫杀死
国会是逼近杜西宁山的伯纳姆森林
And Birnam Wood is Congress on its way to Dunsinane
三个女巫预言
只有伯纳姆森林到达杜西宁山
麦克白才会落败
你我却远隔重洋
And there you are, an ocean away
怎么就非得隔海相望
Do you have to live an ocean away?
思念原已消散  却又寄来锦书
Thoughts of you subside, then I get another letter
叫我如何放下
And I cannot put the notion away
歇一歇
Take a break
马上就好
I am on my way
晚饭前有个小惊喜  不容等待
There's a little surprise before supper and it cannot wait
我很快就来  别收盘子
I'll be there in just a minute, save my plate
-亚历山大  -来了  来了
- Alexander - Okay, okay
今天是你儿子的九岁生日
Your son is nine years old today
他有话要对说
He has something he'd like to say
练习了一整日
He's been practicing all day
菲利普  开始吧
Philip, take it away
爸爸  爸爸  听好
Daddy, Daddy, look
我叫菲利普  我是个诗人
My name is Philip, I am a poet
我写下这首诗来佐证
I wrote this poem just to show it
我刚满九岁
And I just turned nine
你能作诗  但写不出我的精髓
You can write rhymes but you can't write mine
什么
What!
我学法语  和母亲练钢琴
I practice French and play piano with my mother
我有妹妹  还想要个弟弟
I have a sister, but I want a little brother
好吧
Okay.
我的老爸要建立国家银行
My daddy's trying to start America's bank
一  二  三  四  五
Un, deux, trois, quatre, cinq!
-真棒  -歇一歇
- Bravo! - Take a break
我们的孩子真棒
Hey, our kid is pretty great.
今夏同我们去北部度假
Run away with us for the summer, let's go upstate
伊莱莎  工作让我忙碌难歇
Eliza, I've got so much on my plate
我们可以去探望我的父亲
We can all go stay with my father
-那里有片湖泊  -我知道
- There's a lake I know - I know
-附近还有公园  -我也想去
- In a nearby park - I'd love to go
夜幕落下后我们可以去散步
You and I can go when the night gets dark
我尽量抽时间
I will try to get away
亲爱的亚历山大
My dearest Alexander
你得说服杰斐逊
You must get through to Jefferson
商谈折衷之策  直到达成共识
Sit down with him and compromise. Don't stop till you agree
你最爱的大姨子安洁莉卡提醒你
Your favorite older sister, Angelica, reminds you
有人远隔重洋陪伴着你
There's someone in your corner all the way across the sea
在你两周前的来信中
In a letter I received from you two weeks ago
我注意到多出一个逗号
I noticed a comma in the middle of a phrase
细微不同  千差万别  你可是故意为之
It changed the meaning, did you intend this?
轻轻一笔就倾覆我的天地  你写道
One stroke and you've consumed my waking days, it said:
"亲爱的安洁莉卡"
"My dearest Angelica"
"亲爱的"后面加个逗号
With a comma after "Dearest"
你写道
You've written:
"我的爱人
"My dearest,
安洁莉卡"
Angelica"
总之  我妹妹邀请我
Anyway, all this to say, I'm coming home this summer
今年夏天回娘家
At my sister's invitation
如果你和家人去北部度假  我们就能见面
I'll be there with your family if you make your way upstate
我知道你工作繁忙  我知道你身负重任
I know you're very busy, I know your work's important
但我远渡重洋而来  已迫不及待
But I'm crossing the ocean and I just can't wait
你我不再隔海相望
You won't be an ocean away
相聚近在咫尺
You'll only be a moment away
亚历山大  快下来
Alexander, come downstairs
安洁莉卡今日抵达
Angelica's arriving today
安洁莉卡
Angelica
伊莱莎
Eliza!
斯凯勒姐妹
The Schuyler sisters
亚历山大
Alexander
你好
Hi.
见到你真好
It's good to see your face
安洁莉卡  快告诉他
Angelica, tell this man
约翰·亚当斯整个夏天都陪着家人
John Adams spends the summer with his family
安洁莉卡  快告诉我妻子
Angelica, tell my wife
约翰·亚当斯是个闲人  无所事事
John Adams doesn't have a real job anyway
时任副总统
这个职位自创立起就被嘲笑无足轻重
等等  你不和我们同去吗
You're not joining us? Wait
恐怕我不能同你们去北部度假
I'm afraid I cannot join you upstate
亚历山大  我不远万里而来
Alexander, I came all this way
她不远万里而来
She came all this way
不远万里
All this way
歇一歇
Take a break.
我必须要让国会批准我的提案
You know I have to get my plan through congress.
今夏一起去度假  我们去北部
Run away with us for the summer, let's go upstate
如果国会不批准  我会丢掉工作
I lose my job if we don't get this plan through congress
我们可以去探望我们的父亲
We can all go stay with our father
那里有片湖泊
There's a lake I know
你不去我会思念
I know I'll miss your face
附近还有公园
In a nearby park
一鼓作气
Screw your courage to the sticking place
出自《麦克白》
麦克白夫人对麦克白的激励
我们可以去散步
You and I can go
伊莱莎说得对
Eliza's right
歇一歇
Take a break
远走高飞
And get away
今夏一起去度假
Run away with us for the summer
我们去北部
Let's go upstate
我们可以去
Where we can stay
我们可以去探望我们的父亲
We can all go stay with our father
若你放慢步伐
If you take your time
看看如今世事
Look around, look around
此刻我们活着
At how lucky we are
定会千古留名
You will make your mark
是多么幸运
To be alive right now
闭上眼睛畅想
Close your eyes and dream
我们可以去散步
We can go
等夜幕落下
when the night gets dark
歇一歇
Take a break
我必须要让国会批准我的提案
I have to get my plan through Congress.
我不能停歇  直到国会批准我的提案
I can't stop till I get this plan through Congress.
炎炎夏日  无比心浮气躁
There's nothing like summer in the city
重压之下  有人邂逅美女
Someone under stress meets someone looking pretty
风雨欲来  不安空中弥漫
There's trouble in the air, you can smell it
亚历山大  孤独寂寞
And Alexander's by himself
让他来讲
I'll let him tell it
一周没合过眼  心力交瘁  彻夜难寐
I hadn't slept in a week, I was weak, I was awake
私生之子  孤苦之人  亟需喘一口气
You've never seen a bastard orphan more in need of a break
渴望安洁莉卡  思念我的妻子
Longing for Angelica, missing my wife
这时玛丽亚·雷诺兹翩然而至
That's when Miss Maria Reynolds walked into my life
她说
She said:
我知道你是正人君子
I know you are a man of honor
很抱歉我来上门打扰
I'm so sorry to bother you at home
但我走投无路
But I don't know where to go
只身前来见你
And I came here all alone
她说
She said:
我的丈夫辜负与我
My husband's doin' me wrong
拳脚相加  沾花惹草
Beatin' me, cheatin' me
种种虐待
Mistreatin' me
突然之间  他消失无踪
Suddenly he's up and gone
我没有维生的手段
I don't have the means to go on
于是我借钱给她  送她回家
So I offered her a loan, I offered to walk her home
她说
She said:
您真是个好人
You're too kind, sir
我掏出三十块私房钱给她
I gave her 30 bucks that I had socked away
她住在一个街区外  她说
She lived a block away, She said:
我家到了  先生
This one's mine, sir
然后我说  "我该回家了"
Then I said "Well, I should head back home"
她涨红了脸
She turned red
带我走到床边  宽衣解带  并说
She led me to her bed, let her legs spread and said:
别走
Stay?
于是我开始祈祷
That's when I began to pray
主啊  我该如何拒绝
Lord, show me how to say no to this
我不知该如何拒绝
I don't know how to say no to this
天啊  她是如此无助
But, my God, she looks so helpless
她的身体如此火热
And her body's saying, "Hell yes"
不  我该如何拒绝
No, show me how to say no to this
我不知该如何拒绝
I don't know how to say no to this
理智告诉我快走
In my mind, I'm tryin' to go
快走  快走
Go! Go! Go!
然而她吻上我的嘴  我没有说出口
Then her mouth is on mine and I don't say
不要  快拒绝
No! No! Say no to this
我多想说  那是最后一次
I wish I could say that was the last time
说完之后  却一次又一次
I said that last time, it became a pastime
如此一个月后  收信一封
A month into this endeavor I received a letter
寄信人是詹姆斯·雷诺兹  这还没完
From a Mr. James Reynolds, even better
信上写道
It said:
亲爱的先生  展信安
Dear sir, I hope this letter finds you in good health
愿您身居要职  家境富足
And in a prosperous enough position to put wealth
有能力救济我这穷光蛋
In the pockets of people like me down on they luck
要知道  那可是我老婆被你
You see, that was my wife who you decided to...
操
Fu...
戴绿帽子  你可惹错人了
You made the wrong sucker a cuckold
管不住下半身  就要付出代价
So time to pay the piper for the pants you unbuckled
还有  你可以继续见我的荡妇妻子
And, hey, you can keep seein' my whore wife
只要价码合适
if the price is right
否则  我就告诉你妻子
If not, I'm telling your wife
藏好信件  我赶去她的住处
I hid the letter and I raced to her place
冲她大吼  "你干的好事"
Screamed, "How could you?" in her face
她说
She said:
不是我
No, sir
她衣衫不整  态度谦卑
Half-dressed, apologetic
神情慌乱  甚是可怜  她哭喊道
A mess, she looked pathetic, she cried:
求您别走
Please don't go, sir
你编故事骗我
So was your whole story a setup?
信件我毫不知情
I don't know about any letter!
别哭了  站起来
Stop crying, goddamn it, get up
我真的不知情
I didn't know any better!
求你不要把我扔给他
Please don't leave me with him helpless
我完蛋了
I am ruined, I am
我怎能如此愚蠢
How could I do this?
满足他的要求  你就能拥有我
Just give him what he wants and you can have me
我不想要你
I don't want you
你可以随心所欲
Whatever you want
我不想要你
I don't want you
只要你付钱  你就能留下
If you pay, you can stay
主啊  我该如何拒绝
Lord, show me how to say no to this
今晚别走
Tonight
我不知该如何拒绝
I don't know how to say no to this
局面无可奈何
But the situation's helpless
无可奈何
Helpless
她的身体如此火热
And her body's screaming, "Hell yes"
不  我该如何拒绝
No, show me how to say no to this
你要如何拒绝
How can you say no to this?
我该如何拒绝
How can I say no to this?
我已走投无路
There is nowhere I can go
快走  快走
Go, go, go
当她投怀送抱  我没有说出口
When her body's on mine I do not say
不要  快拒绝
No! Say no to this
来啊
Yes
不要  快拒绝
No! Say no to this
来啊
Yes
不要
No!
来啊
Yes
快拒绝
Say no to this
不要
No!
来啊
Yes
快拒绝
Say no to this
我没有拒绝
I don't say no to this
别拒绝
Don't say no to this
我已走投无路
There is nowhere I can go
如何
So?
天知地知
Nobody needs to know
部长先生
Mr. Secretary.
伯尔先生
Mr. Burr, sir.
你听说默瑟将军的消息了吗
Hey, did you hear the news about good old General Mercer?
没有
No.
你知道克莱蒙特大街吧
You know Clermont Street?
知道
Yeah.
现在改成默瑟大街了
They renamed it after him,
默瑟这下千古留名了
the Mercer legacy is secure.
是啊
Sure.
他只是死了而已
And all he had to do was die.
这可真省事
Yeah, that's a lot less work.
我们也该试试
We ought to give it a try.
你打算怎么让国会批准你的提案
Now how you gonna get your debt plan through?
我终归要听你一回
I guess I'm gonna finally have to listen to you.
真的
Really?
少说话
Talk less
多微笑
Smile more
不择手段
Do whatever it takes
让国会批准我的提案
To get my plan on the congress floor
麦迪逊和杰斐逊毫不留情
Now Madison and Jefferson are merciless
常言道  对事不对人
Well, hate the sin, love the sinner
汉密尔顿
Hamilton.
抱歉  伯尔  我得走了
I'm sorry, Burr, I gotta go
但是
Oh, but, uh--
决策将在晚餐期间商讨
Decisions are happening over dinner
"餐桌谈判"上达成"1790妥协"
两个弗吉尼亚人和一个移民走进屋里
Two Virginians and an immigrant walk into a room
势不两立的敌人
Diametrically opposed, foes
却对彼此做出妥协
They emerge with a compromise
打破了之前的僵局
Having opened doors that were previously closed
变兄弟
Bros
这个移民要求前所未有的财政权
The immigrant emerges with unprecedented financial power
随心所欲塑造金融体系
A system he can shape however he wants
弗吉尼亚州人要求定都
The Virginians emerge with the nation's capital
重点在于
And here's the pièce de résistance
决策现场  再无他人
No one else was in the room where it happened
再无他人  再无他人
The room where it happened, the room where it happened
决策现场  再无他人
No one else was in the room where it happened
再无他人  再无他人
The room where it happened, the room where it happened
没人知道游戏规则
No one really knows how the game is played
谈判之道
The art of the trade
个中龌龊
how the sausage gets made
我们只能推测
We just assume that it happens
但是  决策现场  再无他人
But no one else is in the room where it happens
托马斯声称
Thomas claims:
某日亚历山大拜访华盛顿
Alexander was on Washington's doorstep one day,
心慌意乱  满面愁容
in distress and disarray
托马斯声称
Thomas claims:
亚历山大说
Alexander said:
我已走投无路
I have nowhere else to turn
恨不得跪下求我辩论
And basically begged me to join the fray
托马斯声称
Thomas claims:
我去找麦迪逊  并说
I approached Madison and said:
"我知道你讨厌他  但不妨听他说说"
"I know you hate him, but let's hear what he has to say"
托马斯声称
Thomas claims:
我安排了会面
Well, I arranged the meeting
我安排了菜肴  地点  坐席
I arranged the menu, the venue, the seating
但是  决策现场  再无他人
But no one else was in the room where it happened
再无他人  再无他人
The room where it happened, the room where it happened
决策现场  再无他人
No one else was in the room where it happened
再无他人  再无他人
The room where it happened, the room where it happened
无人知晓  具体条件
No one really knows how the parties get to yes
运筹帷幄  如何取舍
The pieces that are sacrificed in every game of chess
我们只能推测
We just assume that it happens
但是  决策现场  再无他人
But no one else is in the room where it happens
与此同时
Meanwhile
麦迪逊逐渐认识到
Madison is grappling with the fact that
民主不是一切问题的答案
not every issue can be settled by committee
与此同时
Meanwhile
国会正为定都何处
Congress is fighting over where to put the capital
吵得不可开交
It isn't pretty.
杰斐逊送出晚餐邀请
Then Jefferson approaches with a dinner and invite
麦迪逊提供弗吉尼亚智慧
And Madison responds with Virginian insight
也许我们可以用一个问题解决另一个
Maybe we can solve one problem with another
为南方人民赢得胜利  换句话说
And win a victory for the Southerners, in other words
-等价交换  -我觉得行
- A quid pro quo. - I suppose.
你想不想工作离家近一点
Wouldn't you like to work a little closer to home?
我还真想
Actually, I would
那我提议波托马克河沿岸
Well, I propose the Potomac
这条河流分隔弗吉尼亚和马里兰
那你为他提供支持
And you'll provide him his votes
我们拭目以待
Well, we'll see how it goes
走吧
Let's go
决策现场  再无他人
No one else was in the room where it happened
再无他人  再无他人
The room where it happened, the room where it happened
决策现场  再无他人
No one else was in the room where it happened
再无他人  再无他人
The room where it happened, the room where it happened
上帝啊
My God
我们信仰上帝
In God we trust
美国的官方格言
无从知晓  交涉内容
But we'll never really know what got discussed
扳机扣动  尘埃落定
Click, boom, then it happened
决策现场  再无他人
And no one else is in the room where it happened
亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Alexander Hamilton
他们开出什么条件
What did they say to you
让你抛下纽约  另选首都
to get you to sell New York City down the river?
亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Alexander Hamilton
华盛顿对晚餐知情吗
Did Washington know about the dinner?
总统有没有暗中施压
Was there presidential pressure to deliver?
亚历山大·汉密尔顿
Alexander Hamilton
还是说你早就知道
Or did you know even then
定都何处无关紧要
It doesn't matter where you put the U.S. Capital?
我们将会建立银行  经济中心仍在纽约
'Cause we'll have the banks, we're in the same spot
你得到的比付出多
You got more than you gave
我得到的正如我愿
And I wanted what I got
不入虎穴  焉得虎子
When you got skin in the game, you stay in the game
置身事外  毫无胜算
But you don't get a win, unless you play in the game
功留美名  过留罪名
Oh, you get love for it, you get hate for it
但你碌碌无名  总在等待  等待  等待
You get nothing if you wait for it, wait for it, wait
上帝宽恕  助我一臂之力
God help and forgive me
我想建立流芳千古的伟业
I wanna build something that's gonna outlive me
你想要什么  伯尔  你想要什么  伯尔
What do you want, Burr? What do you want, Burr?
你没有主张  伯尔  你究竟相信什么
If you stand for nothing, Burr, what do you fall for?
我
I...
我想置身决策现场
I wanna be in the room where it happens
决策现场
The room where it happens
我
I...
我想置身决策现场
wanna be in the room where it happens
决策现场
The room where it happens
我想置身决策现场
I wanna be in the room where it happens
我想置身
I, I wanna be in
决策现场
the room where it happens
我
I...
我想置身决策现场
I wanna be in the room where it happens
我想置身
I wanna be in the room
我想
I wanna be
我要
I've got to be
我要置身
I've got to be in the room
重要的决策现场
that big old room
妥协之计
The art of the compromise
药裹蜜糖
Hold your nose and close your eyes
我们希望领袖力挽狂澜
We want our leaders to save the day
付出什么代价  我们无权过问
But we don't get a say in what they trade away
我们梦想一个新的起点
We dream of a brand-new start
但大多数人只是空想
But we dream in the dark for the most part
决策现场  暗如坟墓
Dark as a tomb where it happens
我要置身
I've got to be in the room
决策现场
The room where it happens
我要
I've got to be
决策现场
The room where it happens
我要
I've got to be
决策现场
The room where it happens
我要置身
I've got to be in the room
决策现场
The room where it happens
我要  我要
I've got to be, I've got to be
决策现场
The room where it happens
我想置身
I wanna be in the room
决策现场
The room where it happens
嘭
Click, boom
看啊  外公上报纸了
Look, Grandpa's in the paper.
"战争英雄菲利普·斯凯勒
"War hero, Philip Schuyler,
参议员席位被政坛新星亚隆·伯尔夺走"
loses Senate seat to young upstart, Aaron Burr."
外公失去了参议员席位
Grandpa just lost his seat in the Senate
有时这也无可奈何
Sometimes that's how it goes
爸爸随时都会得知
Well, Daddy's gonna find out any minute
他肯定早已得知
I'm sure he already knows
接着看
Further down
"纽约州的新参议员隆重登场"
"Let's meet the newest Senator from New York"
纽约
New York
我们的参议员
Our Senator
伯尔  你怎么成了民主共和党人
Burr, since when are you a Democratic-Republican?
因为更改党派让我平步青云
Since being one put me on the up-and-up again
没人了解你的理念  你的政绩
No one knows who you are or what you do
我的事不重要  他们不喜欢你
Hey, they don't need to know me, they don't like you
你说什么
Excuse me
你是华尔街的宠儿
Oh, Wall Street thinks you're great
你的成就将永受爱戴
You'll always be adored by the things you create
但是在北部
But upstate
-等等  -大家都认为你是骗子
- Wait. - People think you're crooked.
斯凯勒的席位不保  我当仁不让
And Schuyler's seat was up for grabs so I took it
我一直把你当作朋友
I've always considered you a friend
我们可以继续做朋友
I don't see why that has to end
你为了跟我岳父竞选  更改党派
You changed parties to run against my father-in-law
我更改党派是为了抓住良机
I changed parties to seize the opportunity I saw
我发誓  你的自尊会害死所有人
I swear, your pride will be the death of us all
出自圣经《箴言》
小心  傲慢必将导致灭亡
Beware, it goeth before the fall
本次的议题是
The issue on the table:
法国即将与英国开战
France is on the verge of war with England.
我们是为法国盟友提供资金和援助
Now, do we commit money and aid to our French allies,
还是坐壁上观
or do we stay out of it?
记住  我对此事的决议
Remember, my decision on this matter
无须经过国会批准
is not subject to congressional approval.
事实上此话不准确
你们只需要说服我
The only one you have to convince is me.
杰斐逊国务卿  请您发言
Secretary Jefferson, you have the floor, sir.
我们命悬一线  亟需帮助之时
When we were on death's door, when we were needy
我们许下承诺  我们签署条约
We made a promise, we signed a treaty
1778年签署的《法美同盟条约》及《友好商业条约》
我们需要钱  需要枪  需要一丝转机
We needed money and guns and half a chance
是谁提供了资金
Uh, who provided those funds?
法国
France.
他们没有要求割地为盟
In return, they didn't ask for land
只要求我们承诺  有朝一日
only a promise that we'd lend a hand
他们反抗压迫者  我们要伸出援手
and stand with them if they fought against oppressors
革命一片混乱
And revolution is messy
但我们该挺身而出
but now is the time to stand
跟我们的兄弟肩并肩  反抗暴政
stand with our brothers as they fight against tyranny
我知道亚历山大·汉密尔顿站在这里
I know that Alexander Hamilton is here
他并不乐意参与这场辩论
And he would rather not have this debate
我要提醒各位  他不是国务卿
I'll remind you that he is not Secretary of State
他不懂忠诚为何物
He knows nothing of loyalty
散发着暴发户气息  穿得好似假冒皇室
Smells like new money, dresses like fake royalty
一心只想出人头地
Desperate to rise above his station
他的一切言行都违背建国理念
Everything he does betrays the ideals of our nation
总统先生  要是你不知道  这下看个清楚
Ay, and if you don't know, now you know, Mr. President
谢谢  杰斐逊国务卿
Thank you, Secretary Jefferson.
汉密尔顿部长  请回应
Secretary Hamilton, your response.
骂他
Get him, boy!
给他好看
Let him know right now.
你一定是脑子进水
You must be outta your goddamn mind
居然认为总统会让我们的国家
If you think the president is gonna bring the nation to the brink
去干涉他国战乱
Of meddling in the middle of a military mess
这盘棋局  法国已丢王弃后
A game of chess, where France is queen and king-less
1793年路易十六被斩首
我们与国王签署条约  但他早已人头落地
We signed a treaty with a king, whose head is now in a basket
你要不要拎起人头  问他意见
Would you like to take it out and ask it
路易国王的脑袋  我们应该遵守条约吗
"Oh, should we honor our treaty, King Louis's head?"
你们随便吧  我早死透了
"Ah, do whatever you want. I'm super dead"
够了  够了
Enough, enough!
-汉密尔顿说得对  -总统先生
- Hamilton is right. - Mr. President--
我们自顾不暇  不能再起战火
We're too fragile to start another fight
先生  难道我们不为自由而战
Sir, do we not fight for freedom?
当然  等法国人选出领袖
Sure, when the French figure out who's gonna lead 'em
人民正在领导
The people are leading
人民正在暴动  两者有所不同
The people are rioting. There's a difference
说实话  这让人有点忧虑
Frankly, it's a little disquieting
你的理念让你看不清现实
You would let your ideals blind you to reality
-汉密尔顿  -长官
- Hamilton? - Sir
1793年  华盛顿颁布《中立宣言》
"对交战双方采取友好和不偏不倚"
成为早期美国的基本外交政策
起草一份中立声明
Draft a statement of neutrality
好的  长官
Yes, sir
难道你忘了拉法耶特
Did you forget Lafayette?
什么
What?
难道你没有一丝歉意
Have you an ounce of regret?
你积累债务  你积聚权力
You accumulate debt. You accumulate power
但在他们需要之时  你却忘恩负义
Yet in their hour of need you forget
拉法耶特是个聪明人  他会理解的
Lafayette's a smart man, he'll be fine
别忘了  我跟他的交情更深
And before he was your friend, he was mine
如果世上每场革命我们都要参与
If we try to fight in every revolution in the world
那么永无止境  何时才能停手
We never stop. Where do we draw the line?
-巧舌如簧  -我承认
- So quick-witted. - Alas, I admit it
-肯定是个好律师  -我的被告都无罪释放
- I bet you were quite a lawyer - My defendants got acquitted
-总得有人提醒你  -什么
- Well, someone ought to remind you - What?
没有华盛顿撑腰  你什么都不是
You're nothing without Washington behind you
-汉密尔顿  -老爸叫你
- Hamilton. - Daddy's calling.
滋味一定不错
It must be nice
有华盛顿给你撑腰
To have Washington on your side
滋味一定不错
It must be nice
有华盛顿给你撑腰
To have Washington on your side
凡事皆有反作用力
Every action has its equal opposite reaction
拜汉密尔顿所赐  我们的内阁派系纷争
Thanks to Hamilton, our cabinet's fractured into factions
只需一点应力
Try not to crack under the stress
就要碎成分数
We're breaking down like fractions
我们在报纸上互相诋毁  谁也不肯退让
We smack each other in the press, and we don't print retractions
我看不惯他突如其来的激情
I get no satisfaction witnessing his fits of passion
油头粉面  品味恶俗
The way he primps and preens and dresses like the pits of fashion
我们穷苦的同胞  农民生活捉肘见襟
Our poorest citizens, our farmers live ration to ration
华尔街大肆劫掠  不放过一毫一厘
as Wall Street robs 'em blind in search of chips to cash in
这个混蛋就是欠教训
This prick is asking for someone to bring him to task
谁给我去挖这个蠢货的黑料
Somebody give me some dirt on this vacuous mass
让我们能够揭露他的真面目
So we can at last unmask him
我愿意扣下扳机
I'll pull the trigger on him
谁来给枪上膛拉栓
Someone load the gun and cock it
我们放任不管  华盛顿被他拉拢
While we were all watching, he got Washington in his pocket
滋味一定不错
It must be nice
有华盛顿给你撑腰
To have Washington on your side
滋味一定不错
It must be nice
有华盛顿给你撑腰
To have Washington on your side
回头看看《权利法案》
Look back at the Bill of Rights
指的应该是《第十修正案》
明确规定联邦政府仅限于《宪法》明文赋予的权力
杰佛逊认为国家银行  以及汉密尔顿的许多政策
都是违反宪法滥用联邦权力
是我写的
Which I wrote
墨迹未干
The ink hasn't dried
滋味一定不错
It must be nice
有华盛顿给你撑腰
To have Washington on your side
他让政府规模翻倍
So he's doubled the size of the government
我们不是刚摆脱日不落政权的统治吗
Wasn't the trouble with much of our previous government size?
-盯住他的双眼  -看他满嘴谎话
- Look in his eyes - See how he lies
审查他的政绩
Follow the scent of his enterprise
集中国债
Centralizing national credit
加强美国信贷
And making American credit competitive
不加制止  就是与之合谋
If we don't stop it we aid and abet it
我必须辞职
I have to resign
必须有人挺身捍卫南方
Somebody has to stand up for the South
必须有人让他哑口无言
Somebody has to stand up to his mouth
想要灭火
If there's a fire you're trying to douse
得先到门外去
You can't put it out from inside the house
我身处内阁
I'm in the cabinet
眼睁睁看他谗言惑君  春风得意
I am complicit in watching him grabbin' at power and kiss it
既然华盛顿心怀偏颇  不听异议
If Washington isn't gon' listen to disciplined dissidents
这事不能忍  老子不干了
This is the difference, this kid is out
这个移民并非我们所选
This immigrant isn't somebody we chose
这个移民让我们惴惴不安
This immigrant's keeping us all on our toes
让这些联邦党人好好长个教训
Let's show these Federalists who they're up against
我们牛逼的南方民主共和党人
Southern motherfukin' Democratic-Republicans
追踪金钱的流向
Now follow the money and see where it goes
因为财政部不断扩张
Because every second the treasury grows
如果我们查出金钱的下落
If we follow the money and see where it leads
掘地三尺  挖出汉密尔顿的罪行
Get in the weeds, look for the seeds of Hamilton's misdeeds
滋味一定不错
It must be nice
追踪金钱的流向
We follow the money and see where it goes
滋味一定不错
It must be nice
皇帝的新衣  我们来戳破
The emperor has no clothes
我们不甘没落
We won't be invisible
我们不容忽视
We won't be denied
不过  滋味一定不错
Still, it must be nice
滋味一定不错
It must be nice
有华盛顿给你撑腰
To have Washington on your side
总统先生  您要见我
Mr. President, you asked to see me.
我知道你很忙
I know you're busy
您有什么需要
What do you need, sir?
长官
Sir?
我想给你提个醒
I wanna give you a word of warning
我不知道您听了什么传言
Sir, I don't know what you heard,
但无论传言怎么说  都是杰斐逊挑起的
but whatever it is, Jefferson started it.
托马斯·杰斐逊今早辞职了
Thomas Jefferson resigned this morning
开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
我需要你帮个忙
I need a favor
任您吩咐  杰斐逊要付出代价
Whatever you say, sir, Jefferson will pay for his behavior
少说话
Shh, talk less
我可以利用报纸  不会透露身份
I'll use the press, I'll write under a pseudonym
等着瞧我批判他的劣行
You'll see what I can do to him
我需要你起草一份致辞
I need you to draft an address
好啊  他辞职了  您终于不用顾忌了
Yes, he resigned, you can finally speak your mind
不  他辞职是为了竞选总统
No, he's stepping down so he can run for president
想打败您  祝他好运
Good luck defeating you, sir.
我要离职  不再参选
I'm stepping down, I'm not running for president
您说什么
I'm sorry, what?
最后一次
One last time
跟我喝一杯  放轻松
Relax, have a drink with me
最后一次
One last time
今晚休息一下
Let's take a break tonight
然后我们要教他们如何告别
And then we'll teach 'em how to say goodbye
如何告别
To say goodbye
你和我
You and I
不  为什么
No, sir. Why?
我想谈谈中立政策
I want to talk about neutrality
长官  英法大战一触即发
Sir, with Britain and France on the verge of war
此时不宜...
Is this the best time--
我想告诫党派斗争
I want to warn against partisan fighting
拿起笔  开始写
Pick up a pen, start writing
我想谈谈一生经验
I wanna talk about what I have learned
教训中积累的智慧
The hard-won wisdom I have earned
在人民心中
As far as the people are concerned
您一定要连任  您完全可以连任
You have to serve, you could continue to serve
不  最后一次
No, one last time
让他们听我谆谆忠告
The people will hear from me
最后一次
One last time
如果做得好
And if we get this right
就能教他们如何告别
We're gonna teach 'em how to say goodbye
你和我
You and I
总统先生  他们会说您软弱
Mr. President, they will say you're weak
不  他们会明白我们的强大
No, they will see we're strong
您的地位独一无二
Your position is so unique
那就发挥作用  让权力交接
So I'll use it to move them along
为什么您一定要离开
Why do you have to say goodbye?
我离开了
If I say goodbye
国家才能前进
the nation learns to move on
我不在了  它也永远繁荣
It outlives me when I'm gone
如同《圣经》所说
Like the scripture says
"人人都在自己的葡萄树和无花果树下安然居住
"Everyone shall sit under their own vine and fig tree
无人惊吓他们"
And no one shall make them afraid"
他们将在我们建立的国家安居乐业
They'll be safe in the nation we've made
我想坐在自己的葡萄树和无花果树下
I want to sit under my own vine and fig tree
在树荫下享片刻安宁
A moment alone in the shade
在我们建立的国家中的家园
At home in this nation we've made
最后一次
One last time
One last time?
1796年9月17日
华盛顿发表著名的《告别辞》
由汉密尔顿撰写
此处节选结尾两段
虽然在检讨本人任期内施政时
Though, in reviewing the incidents of my administration,
我没有发现主观错误
I am unconscious of intentional error,
但是我很清楚自身的缺点
I am nevertheless too sensible of my defects
深知我可能犯过很多错误
not to think it probable that I may have committed many errors.
我也满怀希望
I shall also carry with me the hope
愿我的国家宽恕这些错误
that my country will view them with indulgence...
怀揣一颗赤诚之心  献身为国家服务
And that after 45 years of my life dedicated to its service,
已有四十五年
with an upright zeal,
希望我因为
the faults of incompetent abilities
能力不足而犯的过失
will be consigned to oblivion,
会随着我不久以后
as I myself must soon be
长眠地下而湮灭无闻
to the mansions of rest.
我以欢欣的期待心情
I anticipate with pleasing expectation that retreat...
指望在我切盼实现的退休之后
In which I promise myself to realize the sweet enjoyment
我将与我的同胞们愉快地分享
Of partaking in the midst of my fellow citizens
自由政府治下完善的法律的温暖
The benign influence of good laws under a free government
这是我一直衷心向往的目标
The ever-favorite object of my heart
并且我相信  这也是我们
And the happy reward as I trust
共同努力和赴汤蹈火的优厚报酬
of our mutual cares, labors and dangers
最后一次
One last time
乔治·华盛顿归隐田园
George Washington's going home
教他们如何告别
Teach 'em how to say goodbye
乔治·华盛顿归隐田园
George Washington's going home
你和我
You and I
乔治·华盛顿归隐田园
George Washington's going home
归隐田园
Going home
乔治·华盛顿归隐田园
George Washington's going home
你所做的一切  自有历史评判
History has its eyes on you
乔治·华盛顿归隐田园
George Washington's going home
我们要教他们如何告别
Yeah, we're gonna teach 'em how to say goodbye
教他们如何告别
Teach 'em how to say goodbye
教他们如何告别  如何告别
Teach them how to say goodbye, to say goodbye
教他们如何告别
Teach 'em how to say goodbye
最后一次告别
Say goodbye one last time
最后一次
One last time
Time
他们说
They say
乔治·华盛顿主动让权
George Washington's yielding his power and stepping away
真的吗
Is that true?
我都不知道还能这么做
I wasn't aware that was something a person could do
我好困惑
I'm perplexed
他们要不断更换领袖吗
Are they going to keep on replacing whoever's in charge?
那下一任是谁
If so, who's next?
他们的"国家"中没有别人
There's nobody else in their "country"
如此声名赫赫
Who looms quite as large
什么
What?
约翰·亚当斯
John Adams?
我认识他
I know him
不会吧
That can't be
那个小矮子跟我说过话
That's that little guy who spoke to me
好多年前
All those years ago
哪年来着  1785
What was it? '85
可怜的家伙  肯定要被生吞活剥
That poor man, they're going to eat him alive
沧海桑田  王朝兴替
Oceans rise, empires fall
跟华盛顿相比  他们都毫不起眼
Next to Washington they all look small
孤掌难鸣
All alone
看他们治国
Watch them run
早晚斗个你死我活
They will tear each other into pieces
天呐  等不及看戏了
Jesus Christ, this will be fun
约翰·亚当斯总统
President John Adams?
祝你好运
Good luck.
汉密尔顿  脾气暴躁
How does Hamilton, the short-tempered
反复无常  创建起了
protean creator of the Coast Guard
海岸警卫队  和《纽约时报》
Founder of the New York Post
居然滥用职权  自毁声誉
ardently abuse his cabinet post, destroy his reputation?
欢迎来到亚当斯政府
Welcome, folks, to the Adams administration!
杰斐逊位列第二  担任副总统
Jefferson's the runner-up, which makes him the vice president
华盛顿帮不了你  再无好心总统
Washington can't help you now, no more Mr. Nice President
亚当斯开除汉密尔顿
Adams fires Hamilton
暗地里骂他  加勒比野种
Privately calls him "creole bastard" in his taunts
什么
Say what?
汉密尔顿公开反击
Hamilton publishes his response
给我坐下  约翰  你个肥头大耳的混蛋
Sit down, John, you fat mother--
汉密尔顿狗急跳墙
Hamilton's out of control.
太好了  他无权无势  没有公职
This is great. He's out of power, he holds no office,
还毁了约翰·亚当斯总统
and he just destroyed President John Adams,
其政党仅剩的要员
the only other significant member of his party.
汉密尔顿以一抵百
Hamilton is a host unto himself.
只要手中有笔  就是威胁
As long as he can hold a pen, he's a threat.
我们去找他摊牌
Let's let him know what we know.
副总统先生
Mr. Vice President
麦迪逊先生
Mr. Madison
伯尔参议员
Senator Burr
有何贵干
What is this?
我们手握多个账户的支票存根
We have the check stubs from separate accounts
金额不一  合计近一千美元
Almost a thousand dollars paid in different amounts
于1791年  支付给詹姆斯·雷诺兹先生
To a Mr. James Reynolds way back in 1791
这就是你们手中的把柄  说完了吗
Is that what you have? Are you done?
身为财政要员  你地位特殊
You are uniquely situated by virtue of your position
然而此事跟"品德"毫不沾边
Though "virtue" is not a word I'd apply to this situation
贪图金钱利益  背离神圣使命
To seek financial gain astray from your sacred mission
雷诺兹因投机倒把入狱
谎称汉密尔顿也参与其中
还有证据表明你投机倒把
And the evidence suggests you've engaged in speculation
身为移民  侵吞政府资金
An immigrant embezzling our government funds
你的倒台  已成定局
I can almost see the headline your career is done
希望你给儿女留了口粮
I hope you saved some money for your daughter and sons
你最好从哪来的回哪去
You best g'wan run back where you come from
你们甚至不知道想让我坦白什么
You don't even know what you're asking me to confess
坦白
Confess
你们空口无凭  我不必多说
You have nothing I don't have to tell you anything at all
-除非  -除非
- Unless - Unless
如果我能自证从未犯法
If I can prove that I never broke the law
你们能保证对此事守口如瓶吗
Do you promise not to tell another soul what you saw?
决策现场  再无他人
No one else was in the room where it happened
能保证吗
Is that a yes?
能啊
Um, yes.
"亲爱的先生  展信安
"Dear sir, I hope this letter finds you in good health
愿您身居要职  家境富足
And in a prosperous enough position to put wealth
有能力救济我这穷光蛋
In the pockets of people like me down on their luck
要知道  那可是我老婆被你..."
You see, that was my wife who you decided to--"
什么
What?
她引诱我  骗我上床
She courted me, escorted me to bed
逼我走投无路
And when she had me in a corner
被雷诺兹勒索
That's when Reynolds extorted me
索要钱财  我按季支付
For a sordid fee, I paid him quarterly
就算我的仕途无光
I may have mortally wounded my prospects
但是我的账目明晰
But my papers are orderly
如你们所见
As you can see,
我的每笔开销都有记录
I kept a record of every check in my checkered history
你们自己核查  没有弄虚作假
Check it again against your list and see consistency
我花的每一分都是自己的钱
I never spent a cent that wasn't mine
你们派人调查  我不介意
You sent the dogs after my scent, that's fine
对  我于心有愧
Yes, I have reasons for shame
但我没有犯叛国罪  没有糟蹋自己的名声
But I have not committed treason and sullied my good name
如你们所见
As you can see,
我没干违法乱纪的勾当
I have done nothing to provoke legal action
这个回答你们满意了吗
Are my answers to your satisfaction?
天呐
My God.
先生们  我们走
Gentlemen, let's go.
如何
So?
我们会守口如瓶
The people won't know what we know
伯尔
Burr.
我怎么知道下次针锋相对时
How do I know you won't use this against me
你不会以此对付我
The next time we go toe to toe?
亚历山大  谣言不胫而走
Alexander, rumors only grow
而我们心照不宣
And we both know what we know
飓风之眼  反而宁静
In the eye of a hurricane, there is quiet
稍纵即逝
For just a moment
天空昏黄
A yellow sky
十七岁时  飓风摧毁家乡
When I was 17, a hurricane destroyed my town
我没淹死
I didn't drown
仿佛不死之身
I couldn't seem to die
我用笔墨开拓出路
I wrote my way out
写我目之所及
Wrote everything down far as I could see
我用笔墨开拓出路
I wrote my way out
我抬起头  乡亲注视着我
I looked up and the town had its eyes on me
他们自发募捐
They passed a plate around
素不相识的人
And total strangers
被我的故事
Moved to kindness
激发出善意
By my story
筹款为我购买船票
Raised enough for me to book passage on a ship
前往纽约
that was New York-bound
我用笔墨走出困境  我用笔墨推动革命
I wrote my way out of hell, I wrote my way to revolution
我比自由钟还要响亮
I was louder than the crack in the bell
我给伊莱莎写信  赢得她的芳心
I wrote Eliza love letters until she fell
我声援宪法  誓死捍卫
I wrote about the Constitution and defended it well
面对愚昧和抗拒
And in the face of ignorance and resistance
我创建金融体系
I wrote financial systems into existence
我向上帝祈祷  却毫无回应
And when my prayers to God were met with indifference
我拿起笔  自我救赎
I picked up a pen, I wrote my own deliverance
飓风之眼  反而宁静
In the eye of a hurricane, there is quiet
稍纵即逝
For just a moment
天空昏黄
A yellow sky
十二岁时  母亲去世  她抱着我
I was 12 when my mother died, she was holding me
我们病重  她抱着我
We were sick and she was holding me
仿佛不死之身
I couldn't seem to die
等待  等待  等待
Wait for it, wait for it, wait for it
我要用笔墨开拓出路
I'll write my way out
等待  等待  等待
Wait for it, wait for it, wait for it
写我目之所及
Write everything down far as I can see
等待  等待  等待  等待
Wait for it, wait for it. Wait for it, wait for it
你所做的一切  自有历史评判
History has its eyes on you
我要用笔墨开拓出路
I'll write my way out
用诚实压倒一切
Overwhelm them with honesty
这是飓风之眼
This is the eye of the hurricane
这是我维护功绩的唯一出路
This is the only way I can protect my legacy
等待  等待  等待  等待
Wait for it, wait for it, wait for it. Wait
雷诺兹手册
The Reynolds pamphlet.
The Reynolds pamphlet
你看了吗
Have you read this?
亚历山大·汉密尔顿有一段风流韵事
Alexander Hamilton had a torrid affair
他全写出来了
And he wrote it down right there
精彩节选
Highlights!
"有人指控我与詹姆斯·雷诺兹勾结
"The charge against me is a connection with one James Reynolds
行投机倒把之事
For purposes of improper speculation
但我真正的罪行是与他的妻子苟合
My real crime is an amorous connection with his wife
关系长期维持  且他知情同意"
For a considerable time with his knowing consent"
该死
Damn
"我与她私会频繁  通常在我家里"
"I had frequent meetings with her, most of them at my own house"
-在他家里  -在他家里
- At his own house - At his own house
该死
Damn
"汉密尔顿夫人携带儿女
"Mrs. Hamilton, with our children
离家拜访她的父亲"
Being absent on a visit to her father"
不是吧
No
你看了吗
Have you read this?
别想当总统了
He's never gon' be president now
Never gon' be president now
别想当总统了
Well, never gon' be president now
Never gon' be president now
少了一件忧心事
That's one less thing to worry about
-我一听到消息就来了  -什么
- I came as soon as I heard. - What?
安洁莉卡从伦敦远道而来
Angelica all the way from London?
该死
Damn!
安洁莉卡  谢天谢地  终于有人理解
Angelica, thank God someone who understands
我为何苦苦抗争
What I'm struggling here to do
我不是为你而来
I'm not here for you.
我对我妹妹了如指掌
I know my sister like I know my own mind
再也不会有人像她那般纯真善良
You will never find anyone as trusting or as kind
我爱我妹妹胜过一切
I love my sister more than anything in this life
我永远把她的幸福放在第一位
I will choose her happiness over mine every time
忘了我们的交情  我只支持她一人
Put what we had aside, I'm standing at her side
你永远不懂满足  希望你现在满足了
You could never be satisfied. God, I hope you're satisfied
别想当总统了
He's never gon' be president now
Never gon' be president now
别想当总统了
He's never gon' be president now
Never gon' be president now
别想当总统了
He's never gon' be president now
Never gon' be president now
少了一件忧心事
That's one less thing to worry about
别想当总统了
He's never gon' be president now
至少他没挪用公款
At least he was honest with our money
少了一件忧心事
That's one less thing to worry about
雷诺兹手册
The Reynolds pamphlet.
你看了吗
Have you read this?
你见过有谁自毁人生吗
You ever see somebody ruin their own life?
他可怜的妻子
His poor wife
我留着你写给我的每一封信
I saved every letter you wrote me
读起它们  我知道你属于我
From the moment I read them I knew you were mine
你说过你属于我
You said you were mine
我以为你属于我
I thought you were mine
你知道收到你的第一封信时
Do you know what Angelica said
安洁莉卡怎么说吗
When we saw your first letter arrive?
她说  "小心那个人  亲爱的
She said "Be careful with that one, love
他为了生存会不择手段"
He will do what it takes to survive"
你和你的文字令我深深陶醉
You and your words flooded my senses
完全卸下防备
Your sentences left me defenseless
你为我编织空中楼阁
You built me palaces out of paragraphs
塑造盲目崇拜
You built cathedrals
我重读你写给我的信
I'm rereading the letters you wrote me
我在搜索答案
I'm searching and scanning for answers
寻找蛛丝马迹
In every line for some kind of sign
曾经你属于我
And when you were mine
整个世界似乎
The world seemed
熊熊燃烧
To burn
Burn
你公开她写给你的信
You published the letters she wrote you
你告诉整个世界  如何把她带上我们的床
You told the whole world how you brought this girl into our bed
以此为你正名
In clearing your name
却毁了我们的生活
You have ruined our lives
你知道安洁莉卡读后
Do you know what Angelica said
说了什么吗
When she read what you'd done?
她说  "你嫁给了伊卡洛斯
She said, "You've married an Icarus
他飞近太阳坠海而死"
He's flown too close to the sun"
你和你的话语  总围绕着功绩
You and your words obsessed with your legacy
你的文字语无伦次
Your sentences border on senseless
字里行间偏执多疑
And you are paranoid in every paragraph
只顾世人如何看你
How they perceive you
全是你  只有你
You, you, you
我要从史书中抹去自己
I'm erasing myself from the narrative
让未来的史学家去琢磨你让伊莱莎心碎时
Let future historians wonder how Eliza reacted
她作何反应
When you broke her heart
你让她彻底心碎
You have torn it all apart
我看着信燃烧殆尽
I'm watching it burn
Watching it burn
这个世界无权了解我的心声
The world has no right to my heart
这个世界无权窥探我家私事
The world has no place in our bed
他们别想读我写过的信
They don't get to know what I said
我要烧掉回忆
I'm burning the memories
烧掉能为你挽回声誉的信
Burning the letters that might have redeemed you
你失去了我心中的地位
You forfeit all rights to my heart
你失去了我枕旁的位置
You forfeit the place in our bed
以后你就睡在办公室吧
You'll sleep in your office instead
你我之间
With only the memories
只剩回忆
Of when you were mine
我希望你
I hope that you
万劫不复
Burn
有请国王学院新鲜出炉的毕业生
Meet the latest graduate of King's College
我多半不该吹嘘
I probably shouldn't brag
真该死  我这么出色
But dag, I amaze and astonish
学者们说我的才干媲美老爸
The scholars say I got the same virtuosity and brains as my pops
姑娘们说我的魅力也不逊色
The ladies say my brain's not where the resemblance stops
年方十九  思想成熟
I'm only 19, but my mind is older
我得自食其力  青出于蓝而胜于蓝
Gotta be my own man, like my father, but bolder
我骄傲地继承他的功绩
I shoulder his legacy with pride
我曾听他说过  有朝一日
I used to hear him say that someday I would...
我将震撼环宇
Blow us all away
女士们  我找乔治·伊克先生
Ladies, I'm looking for a Mr. George Eacker
上周国庆日演说的那位
Made a speech last week, our Fourth of July speaker
他在众人面前贬低我父亲的功绩
He disparaged my father's legacy In front of a crowd
我无法忍受  我要让父亲骄傲
I can't have that, I'm making my father proud
我看他去了百老汇那边
I saw him just up Broadway a couple of blocks
他要去看戏
He was going to see a play
那我去包厢找他
Well, I'll go visit his box
天啊  你可真是迷人
God, you're a fox
你们的打扮也不赖
Y'all look pretty good in your frocks
等我回来  咱们都把衣服脱光吧
How 'bout when I get back we all strip down to our socks?
好啊
Okay!
震撼环宇
Blow us all away
乔治
George!
-乔治  -我在看戏呢
- George. - I'm trying to watch the show.
你早该管好你的嘴
You should've watched your mouth
少嚼我父亲的舌根
Before you talked about my father though
我可没说不实之事
I didn't say anything that wasn't true
你父亲是个无赖  看来你也一样
Your father's a scoundrel and so, it seems, are you
-你认真的  -对  我可没开玩笑
- It's like that? - Yeah, I don't fool around
我可不是学校里的小朋友
I'm not your little schoolboy friends
那就决斗场上见
Well, see you on the dueling ground
除非你想现在就出去比试一番
That is, unless you wanna step outside and go now
我知道去哪找到你  滚吧  我在看戏呢
I know where to find you, piss off, I'm watching the show now
老爸  你要是听到他的言论
Pops, if you had only heard the shit he said about you
肯定不会置之不理  我也一样
I doubt you would have let it slide and I was not about to
-慢着  -我来寻求你的建议
- Slow down. - I came to ask you for advice
这是我的第一场决斗
This is my very first duel
寄宿学校没有这门课
They don't exactly cover this subject in boarding school
你的朋友尝试讲和了吗
Did your friends attempt to negotiate a peace?
他拒绝道歉  讲和是不可能了
He refused to apologize. We had to let the peace talks cease
-决斗地点在哪  -河对岸  新泽西
- Where is this happening? - Across the river, in Jersey
在新泽西一切都是合法的
Everything is legal in New Jersey
好吧
All right
你要照我说的做
So, this is what you're gonna do
像个男人一样面对伊克
Stand there like a man until Eacker is in front of you
待时机到来  瞄准天空开枪
When the time comes, fire your weapon in the air
圆满解决这件事
This will put an end to the whole affair
万一他决定对我开枪  我就死定了
But what if he decides to shoot? Then I'm a goner
不  如果他是正人君子  他也会照做
No, he'll follow suit if he's truly a man of honor
夺取他人性命  罪孽深重无法摆脱
To take someone's life, that is something you can't shake
菲利普  你母亲承受不了再次心碎
Philip, your mother can't take another heartbreak
除了显而易见的心碎之外
安洁莉卡的妹妹佩吉·斯凯勒于1801年去世
-父亲  -答应我
- Father-- - Promise me
别让你的良心沾上这位年轻人的鲜血
You don't want this young man's blood on your conscience
好的  我答应
Okay, I promise
结束之后就回家来
Come back home when you're done
拿上我的枪  机灵点
Take my guns, be smart
要让我骄傲  孩子
Make me proud, son
我叫菲利普  我是个诗人
My name is Philip, I am a poet
我有点紧张  但不能表露
And I'm a little nervous but I can't show it
抱歉  我是汉密尔顿骄傲的后人
I'm sorry, I'm a Hamilton with pride
你诽谤我父亲  我不能置之不理
You talk about my father, I cannot let it slide
伊克先生  你的戏看得怎么样
Mr. Eacker, how was the rest of your show?
我不想寒暄  开始吧
I'd rather skip the pleasantries. Let's go
-拿好你的枪  -和同伴商量好
- Grab your pistol. - Confer with your men
数到十后决斗开始
The duel will commence after we count to ten
数到十
Count to ten
盯着对方的眼睛  别瞄高了
Look 'em in the eye, aim no higher
鼓起全部勇气
Summon all the courage you require
然后缓慢坚定地  举枪瞄准天空
Then slowly and clearly, aim your gun towards the sky
一  二  三  四  五  六  七
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
活下去
Stay alive
我儿子在哪
Where's my son?
汉密尔顿先生  请进
Mr. Hamilton, come in.
他是半小时前被送来的
They brought him in a half an hour ago.
他在途中失血很多
He lost a lot of blood on the way over.
-他还活着吗  -是的
- Is he alive? - Yes.
但你要明白
But you have to understand,
子弹从臀部上方射入  卡在他的右臂
the bullet entered just above his hip and lodged in his right arm.
-我能看看他吗  -我在全力救治
- Can I see him, please? - I'm doing everything I can.
但是他抵达时  伤口已经感染
But the wound was already infected when he arrived.
菲利普
Philip.
爸
Pa.
我完全照你说的做了  爸
I did exactly as you said, Pa
我昂首挺胸
I held my head up high
我明白  我明白
I know, I know, shh
-昂首挺胸  -我明白  我明白
- High. - I know, I know, shh
我明白你做得很好
I know you did everything just right
还没数到十
Even before we got to ten
我就瞄准了天空
I was aiming for the sky
我明白  我明白
I know, I know, shh
-我瞄准了天...  -我明白  我明白
- I was aiming for the s-- - I know, I know, shh
我明白  保存体力  活下去
I know, save your strength and stay alive
不
No!
伊莱莎
Eliza
他还有呼吸吗  他能活下去吗
Is he breathing? Is he going to survive this?
活下去
Stay alive
这是谁干的
Who did this?
亚历山大  你知道吗
Alexander, did you know?
妈妈  我很抱歉
Mom, I'm so sorry
忘记了你的教导
For forgetting what you taught me
我的儿子
My son
-我们弹钢琴  -我教你钢琴
- We played piano. - I taught you piano
你手把手教我
You would put your hands on mine
你每次都改变旋律
You changed the melody every time
我总是弹别的段落
I would always change the line
我明白  我明白
Shh, I know, I know
我总是弹别的段落
I would always change the line
我明白  我明白
I know, I know.
一  二  三  四  五  六  七  八  九
Un, deux, trois, quatre, cinq, six, sept, huit, neuf
Un, deux, trois, quatre Cinq, six, sept, huit, neuf
很好
Good
一  二  三  四  五  六  七  八  九
Un, deux, trois, quatre, cinq, six, sept, huit, neuf
一  二  三...
Un, deux, trois...
七  八  九
Sept, huit, neuf.
七  八...
Sept, huit...
有些时刻难以描述
There are moments that the words don't reach
有些哀痛难以言说
There is suffering too terrible to name
用力抱紧你的孩子
You hold your child as tight as you can
试图抵挡无妄之灾
And push away the unimaginable
深陷悲怆难以自拔
The moments when you're in so deep
索性从此消沉下去
It feels easier to just swim down
汉密尔顿一家搬到城郊
The Hamiltons move uptown
试图接受无妄之灾
And learn to live with the unimaginable
我在花园消磨时间
I spend hours in the garden
我独自步行去商店
I walk alone to the store
城郊静悄悄
And it's quiet uptown
我以前并不喜欢宁静
I never liked the quiet before
周日带孩子们去教堂
I take the children to church on Sunday
站在门前的十字架前
A sign of the cross at the door
我默默祈祷
And I pray
我以前从不祈祷
That never used to happen before
如果你在街上看到他
If you see him in the street
形影单只
Walking by himself
自言自语
Talking to himself
请怀恻隐之心
Have pity
菲利普  你一定喜欢城郊  城郊静悄悄
Philip, you would like it uptown. It's quiet uptown
他遭遇了无妄之灾
He is working through the unimaginable
他须发渐白
His hair has gone grey
他日日徘徊
He passes every day
人们说他走遍整座城市
They say he walks the length of the city
我无力抗拒
You knock me out
我痛不欲生
I fall apart
你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
看看我们如今的境遇
Look at where we are
想想我们曾阖家幸福
Look at where we started
我知道我配不上你  伊莱莎
I know I don't deserve you, Eliza
但若你肯听我说
But hear me out
那便已足够
That would be enough
如果我能救他一命
If I could spare his life
如果我能以命抵命
If I could trade his life for mine
那他就会站在这里
He'd be standing here right now
你便会展露笑颜
And you would smile
那便已足够
And that would be enough
我不会假装理解
I don't pretend to know
我们面临的困难
The challenges we're facing
我知道我们失去的
I know there's no replacing
无可替代
What we've lost
你也需要时间
And you need time
但我无所畏惧
But I'm not afraid
我了解我的妻子
I know who I married
只要让我陪在你身边
Just let me stay here by your side
那便已足够
That would be enough
如果你在街上看到他
If you see him in the street
伴她左右
Walking by her side
陪她说话
Talking by her side
请怀恻隐之心
Have pity
伊莱莎  你喜欢城郊吗  城郊静悄悄
Eliza, do you like it uptown? It's quiet uptown
他在接受无妄之灾
He is trying to do the unimaginable
他们漫步在公园里
See them walking in the park
在夜深人静时
Long after dark
看遍城市风景
Taking in the sights of the city
看看如今世事  伊莱莎
Look around, look around, Eliza
他们在接受无妄之灾
They are trying to do the unimaginable
有些时刻难以描述
There are moments that the words don't reach
有些慈悲难以言说
There's a grace too powerful to name
我们放下心中困惑
We push away what we can never understand
我们放下无妄之灾
We push away the unimaginable
他们伫立在花园中
They are standing in the garden
亚历山大陪着伊莱莎
Alexander by Eliza's side
她握住他的手
She takes his hand
城郊静悄悄
It's quiet uptown
宽恕
Forgiveness
你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
宽恕
Forgiveness
你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
如果你在街上看到他
If you see him in the street
伴她左右
Walking by her side
陪她说话
Talking by her side
请怀恻隐之心
Have pity
他们遭遇了无妄之灾
They are going through the unimaginable
1800年大选
The election of 1800.
-我们能说回政事吗  -拜托了
- Can we get back to politics? - Uh, please.
凡事皆有反作用力
Yo, every action has its equal opposite reaction
约翰·亚当斯声名狼藉
John Adams shat the bed
我喜欢他  但他举步维艰
I love the guy, but he's in traction
可怜的亚历山大·汉密尔顿已无暇政事
Poor Alexander Hamilton, he is missing in action
所以我的对手是亚隆·伯尔
So now I'm facing Aaron Burr
和他的帮派
With his own faction
他在北方万众瞩目  纽约人都看好他
He's very attractive in the north, New Yorkers like his chances
他从不表明自己的立场
He's not very forthcoming on any particular stances
向他询问  他闪烁其词  避而不谈
Ask him a question, it glances off, he obfuscates, he dances
他们说我是亲法派
And they say I'm a Francophile
至少他们清楚我知道法国在哪
At least they know I know where France is
托马斯  这就是问题所在
Thomas, that's the problem, see
他们认为伯尔比你温和
They see Burr as a less extreme you
你要改变策略
You need to change course,
找个大人物挽回你的形象
a key endorsement might redeem you
你看中哪位了
Who did you have in mind?
-说出来你别笑  -哪位
- Don't laugh. - Who is it?
你们曾共事过
You used to work on the same staff.
-不会吧  -说不定是好事
- What? - It might be nice
说不定是好事
It might be nice
有汉密尔顿给你撑腰
To get Hamilton on your side
说不定是好事
It might be nice
有汉密尔顿给你撑腰
To get Hamilton on your side
少说话
Talk less
多微笑
Smile more!
别向他们表露你的喜恶
Don't let them know what you're against or what you're for
与人握手
Shake hands with him
向人示好
Charm her
1800年了  女士们  让你们的丈夫投伯尔一票
It's 1800. Ladies, tell your husbands, "Vote for Burr!"
我不喜欢亚当斯
I don't like Adams.
他赢不了  失败者注定失败
Well, he's gonna lose. That's just defeatist.
杰斐逊呢
And Jefferson?
-他对法国情有独钟  -他太恃才傲物
- In love with France. - Yeah, he's so elitist.
我喜欢亚隆·伯尔
I like that Aaron Burr.
不敢相信他就在我们身边
I can't believe we're here with him.
他看起来平易近人
He seems approachable.
好像你能同他共饮一杯
Like you could grab a beer with him.
亲爱的汉密尔顿先生  你的联邦党同僚
Dear Mr. Hamilton, your fellow Federalists
想知道你会投给谁
Would like to know how you'll be voting
城郊静悄悄
It's quiet uptown
亲爱的汉密尔顿先生  约翰·亚当斯毫无胜算
Dear Mr. Hamilton, John Adams doesn't stand a chance
你会支持谁
So who are you promoting
城郊静悄悄
It's quiet uptown
杰斐逊还是伯尔
Jefferson or Burr
我们知道  都是你的宿敌
We know it's lose-lose
杰弗逊还是伯尔
Jefferson or Burr
如果你必须做出选择
But if you had to choose
亲爱的汉密尔顿先生
Dear Mr. Hamilton
约翰·亚当斯毫无胜算
John Adams doesn't stand a chance
你会支持谁
So who are you promoting?
如果你必须做出选择
But if you had to choose?
这不是亚隆·伯尔先生吗
Well, if it isn't Aaron Burr, sir
-亚历山大  -您真是大闹一出啊
- Alexander! - You've created quite a stir, sir
-我在挨家挨户拉票  -你在公开竞选
- I'm going door-to-door - You're openly campaigning?
-是啊  -真新奇
- Sure - That's new
老实说  这还挺磨人
Honestly, it's kind of draining
-伯尔  -先生
- Burr. - Sir.
你可真是无所不用其极
Is there anything you wouldn't do?
不  我在追求心中所愿
No. I'm chasing what I want.
-你知道吗  -什么
- And you know what? - What?
我是跟你学的
I learned that from you.
如果你必须做出选择
If you had to choose
打成平局
It's a tie.
如果你必须做出选择
If you had to choose
胜负取决于代表们
It's up to the delegates.
如果你必须做出选择
If you had to choose
胜负取决于汉密尔顿
It's up to Hamilton!
如果你必须做出选择
If you had to choose
杰弗逊还是伯尔
Jefferson or Burr
选择  选择  选择
Choose, choose, choose
人民询问我的意见
The people are asking to hear my voice
国家正面临艰难的抉择
The country is facing a difficult choice
如果你要问我支持谁
And if you were to ask me who I'd promote
我投给杰斐逊
Jefferson has my vote.
我与杰斐逊向来不合
I have never agreed with Jefferson once
我们就像针尖对麦芒
We have fought on like, 75 different fronts
但归根结底
But when all is said and all is done
杰斐逊信守理念
Jefferson has beliefs
伯尔毫无底线
Burr has none
万万没想到
Well, I'll be damned
有汉密尔顿给你撑腰
Hamilton's on your side
万万没想到
Well, I'll be damned
然后呢
And?
你获得压倒性胜利
You won in a landslide.
祝贺你获得胜利
Congrats on a race well run
我是个难缠的对手
I did give you a fight
我期待我们的合作
I look forward to our partnership.
-合作  -作为你的副总统
- Our partnership? - As your vice president.
得了吧
Yeah, right.
你听到他说的了吗
You hear this guy?
这人公开与我竞争
Man openly campaigns against me,
好意思说期待与我合作
talkin' 'bout, "I look forward to our partnership."
让第二名来当副总统
It is crazy that the guy who comes in second
这规则太疯狂了
gets to be vice president.
你知道吗  我们可以改变规则
You know what? We can change that.
-知道为什么吗  -为什么
- You know why? - Why?
因为我是总统
'Cause I'm the president.
伯尔  等你见到汉密尔顿
Burr, uh, when you see Hamilton,
替我谢谢他的支持
thank him for the endorsement.
汉密尔顿
How does Hamilton
傲慢之人  移民孤儿  荡妇之子
An arrogant, immigrant, orphan, bastard, whore's son
竟然支持他的宿敌  托马斯·杰斐逊
Somehow endorse Thomas Jefferson, his enemy
他从一开始就鄙视的人
A man he's despised since the beginning
就是为了不让我赢
Just to keep me from winning?
我想置身决策现场
I wanna be in the room where it happens
决策现场
The room where it happens
这是你最后一次阻碍我
You've kept me from the room where it happens
置身决策现场
For the last time
亲爱的亚历山大
Dear Alexander
我不轻易动怒
I am slow to anger
但我忍无可忍
But I toe the line
我意识到人生处处受你阻碍
As I reckon with the effects of your life on mine
回顾我的失败
I look back on where I failed
思前想后
And in every place I checked
从头到尾你都未曾尊重过我
The only common thread has been your disrespect
如今你说我道德败坏
Now you call me amoral
说我是危险小人
A dangerous disgrace
如果你对我有意见
If you've got something to say
定好时间地点  当面说清
Name a time and place face-to-face
您顺从的仆人
I have the honor to be your obedient servant
亚·伯尔
A dot Burr
副总统先生
Mr. Vice President
没人信任你  这不能怪我
I am not the reason no one trusts you
没人知道你的居心
No one knows what you believe
我不会含糊其辞
I will not equivocate on my opinion
我总是直抒己见
I have always worn it on my sleeve
即使你说的确有发生
Even if I said what you think I said
你也要指明具体事件
You would need to cite a more specific grievance
这里列出了我们三十年来的分歧
Here's an itemized list of 30 years of disagreements
老天
Sweet Jesus.
我没有回避
Hey, I have not been shy
我是个公众人物
I am just a guy in the public eye
为国家拼尽全力
Trying to do my best for our republic
我无意争执
I don't wanna fight
我秉公为国  不会道歉
But I won't apologize for doing what's right
您顺从的仆人
I have the honor to be your obedient servant
亚·汉
A dot Ham
小心你的言辞  大好人
Careful how you proceed, good man
不要欺人太甚  大好人
Intemperate indeed, good man
回应我对你的指控
Answer for the accusations I lay at your feet
不然就做好流血的准备  大好人
Or prepare to bleed, good man
伯尔  你的控诉合情合理
Burr, your grievance is legitimate
我为我的言论负责  坚持立场
I stand by what I said, every bit of it
你只在乎自己的利益  向来如此
You stand only for yourself. It's what you do
这是事实  我不会道歉
I can't apologize because it's true
那就坚持到底  亚历山大
Then stand, Alexander.
黎明时分  威霍肯见
Weehawken. Dawn.
备好枪支
Guns. Drawn.
说定了
You're on.
您顺从的仆人
I have the honor to be your obedient servant
亚·汉
A dot Ham
亚·伯尔
A dot Burr
亚历山大  回来睡觉
Alexander, come back to sleep
我一早要出城会面
I have an early meeting out of town
-天还没亮  -我知道
- It's still dark outside. - I know.
我只是需要写点东西
I just need to write something down
为何笔耕不辍  仿佛时日无多
Why do you write like you're running out of time?
回来睡觉  那便已足够
Come back to bed. That would be enough
你一眨眼我就回来了
I'll be back before you know I'm gone
回来睡觉
Come back to sleep
会面定在黎明
This meeting's at dawn
那我回去睡了
Well, I'm going back to sleep
最好的妻子  最好的女人
Best of wives and best of women
一  二  三  四  五  六  七  八  九
One, two, three, four Five, six, seven, eight, nine
十个要点不得不说
There are ten things you need to know
第一
Number one
黎明时分我们横渡哈德逊河
We rowed across the Hudson at dawn
我的朋友威廉·P·范内斯担当我的副手
My friend, William P. Van Ness signed on as my number two
第二
Number two
汉密尔顿一行人到达
Hamilton arrived with his crew
纳森尼尔·彭德尔顿和熟识的医生随行
Nathaniel Pendleton and a doctor that he knew
第三
Number three
我看着汉密尔顿审视地形
I watched Hamilton examine the terrain
真想知道此刻他脑中的念头
I wish I could tell you what was happening in his brain
此人害我政治前程尽毁
This man has poisoned my political pursuits
多数纷争  不战而消
Most disputes die, and no one shoots
第四
Number four
汉密尔顿稳稳站定
Hamilton drew first position
神情严肃  仿佛身负使命
Looking to the world like a man on a mission
这是个弹无虚发的士兵
This is a soldier with a marksman's ability
医生转身  方便事后推诿
The doctor turned around so he could have deniability
第五
Five
当时我并不知道
Now, I didn't know this at the time
我们正站在你儿子丧命之处
But we were near the same spot your son died
也许这就为何
Is that why
第六
Six
他如此慎重地检查枪支
He examined his gun with such rigor?
我看着他有条不紊地摆弄扳机
I watched as he methodically fiddled with the trigger
第七
Seven
该坦白了  我得说实话
Confession time. Here's what I got
我的战友都知道我枪法差劲
My fellow soldiers'll tell you I'm a terrible shot
此话不实
第八
Number eight
最后的协商机会
Your last chance to negotiate
派出副手
Send in your seconds
看是否能澄清误会
See if they can set the record straight
历史课上不会教这个
They won't teach you this in your classes
你们去查查  汉密尔顿当时把眼镜戴起
But look it up, Hamilton was wearing his glasses
难道不是为了将我毙命于抢下
Why, if not to take deadly aim?
一山不容二虎  世界从此不同
It's him or me. The world will never be the same
开枪之前我只有一个念头
I had only one thought before the slaughter
此人休想让我女儿沦为孤儿
This man will not make an orphan of my daughter
第九
Number nine
盯着对方的眼睛  别瞄高了
Look him in the eyes, aim no higher
鼓起全部勇气
Summon all the courage you require
然后数数
Then count
一  二  三  四  五  六  七  八  九
One, two, three, four Five, six, seven, eight, nine
-几步  -十步
- Number! - Ten paces!
开枪
Fire!
我时常想象死亡  熟悉得如同回忆
I imagine death so much it feels more like a memory
这就是我的死期吗
Is this where it gets me
站着等子弹袭来
On my feet, several feet ahead of me?
我看着它逼近
I see it coming
是该逃跑  反击  还是认命
Do I run or fire my gun or let it be?
没有鼓点  没有旋律
There is no beat, no melody
伯尔  我最初的朋友  我的宿敌
Burr, my first friend, my enemy
或许是我死前见到的最后一人
Maybe the last face I ever see
如果我放过良机射偏
If I throw away my shot
世人对我的看法是否将如此被定义
Is this how you remember me?
如果这颗子弹就是我留下的功绩
What if this bullet is my legacy?
功绩
Legacy
何为功绩
What is a legacy?
功绩是殷勤播种  却无缘见其绽放
It's planting seeds in a garden you never get to see
我谱下乐曲的序章
I wrote some notes at the beginning of a song
将由后人来吟唱
someone will sing for me
美利坚  你这曲未完成的宏伟交响
America, you great unfinished symphony
是你召唤我  是你让我有所作为
You sent for me. You let me make a difference
是你让我这个移民孤儿
A place where even orphan immigrants
挥墨史书  出人头地
Can leave their fingerprints and rise up
没时间了  没时间了  我的死期将至
I'm running out of time, I'm running and my time's up
动脑筋  抬起头
Wise up, eyes up
我瞥见另一个世界
I catch a glimpse of the other side
劳伦斯在那边带领士兵们合唱
Laurens leads a soldiers' chorus on the other side
我儿子也在那边
My son is on the other side
他和我母亲在一起
He's with my mother on the other side
华盛顿在那边看着我
Washington is watching from the other side
教他们如何告别
Teach me how to say goodbye
崛起  崛起  崛起
Rise up. Rise up. Rise up.
伊莱莎
Eliza!
亲爱的  尽情享受人生
My love, take your time.
我们另一个世界再会
I'll see you on the other side.
举杯敬自由
Raise a glass to freedom
他举枪瞄准天空
He aims his pistol at the sky.
等等
Wait!
我击中他的肋间
I strike him right between his ribs
我朝他走去  却被催促离开
I walk towards him, but I am ushered away
他们带他渡回哈德逊河对岸
They row him back across the Hudson
我喝了一杯
I get a drink
我听到街上传来哀号
I hear wailing in the streets
有人跟我说  "你最好躲起来"
Somebody tells me, "You'd better hide"
他们说安洁莉卡和伊莱莎
They say Angelica and Eliza
在他临终时都伴在身侧
Were both at his side when he died
死亡不分罪人圣徒
Death doesn't discriminate between the sinners and the saints
它不断索取
It takes and it takes and it takes
历史冲刷掉一幕幕
History obliterates in every picture it paints
加深我的种种过错
It paints me in all my mistakes
亚历山大举枪瞄准天空
When Alexander aimed at the sky
他虽先一步撒手人寰
He may have been the first one to die
我却要苟活赎罪
But I'm the one who paid for it
捡回一命  却罪责难逃
I survived, but I paid for it
我成了你们史书中的罪人
Now I'm the villain in your history
我太年轻盲目  执迷不悟
I was too young and blind to see
我早该知道  我早该知道
I should've known, I should've known
世界之大
The world was wide enough
容得下汉密尔顿和我
For both Hamilton and me
世界之大
The world was wide enough
容得下汉密尔顿和我
For both Hamilton and me
年轻时的我梦想荣耀
Let me tell you what I wish I'd known
多希望那时我就懂得
When I was young and dreamed of glory
你无法左右
You have no control
谁生  谁死  谁讲述你的故事
Who lives? Who dies? Who tells your story?
杰斐逊总统
President Jefferson.
我得承认  他建立的金融系统无人能及
I'll give him this, his financial system is a work of genius.
就算我想方设法也不可能颠覆
I couldn't undo it if I tried.
我可没少尝试
And I tried.
谁生  谁死  谁讲述你的故事
Who lives? Who dies? Who tells your story?
麦迪逊总统
President Madison.
他带领我国从破产走向繁荣
He took our country from bankruptcy to prosperity.
虽然我不想承认  但我们给他的赞誉
I hate to admit it, but he doesn't get enough credit
远不及他给我们的信贷
for all the credit that he gave us.
谁生  谁死  谁讲述你的故事
Who lives? Who dies? Who tells your story?
其他开国元勋的故事都广为传颂
Every other founding father's story gets told
其他开国元勋都得以安然终老
Every other founding father gets to grow old
当你挥别人世  谁铭记你的名字
And when you're gone who remembers your name?
谁继承你的薪火  谁讲述你的故事
Who keeps your flame? Who tells your story?
谁讲述你的故事
Who tells your story?
伊莱莎
Eliza
我重新把自己写进史书
I put myself back in the narrative
伊莱莎
Eliza
我不再浪费时间哭泣
I stop wasting time on tears
我又活了五十年
I live another 50 years
但还远远不够
It's not enough
伊莱莎
Eliza
我采访每一个曾与你并肩作战的士兵
I interview every soldier who fought by your side
她讲述我们的故事
She tells our story
我尽力整理你留下的无数文稿
I try to make sense of your thousands of pages of writings
你确实笔耕不辍  仿佛时日无多
You really do write like you're running out of time
安洁莉卡在世时
I rely on Angelica
是我最大的支柱
While she's alive
我们共同讲述你的故事
We tell your story
她被安葬于三一教堂
She is buried in Trinity Church
在你身旁
Near you
我最需要她的时刻  她从不缺席
When I needed her most she was right on time
但还是不够
And I'm still not through
我自问  "倘若你仍有时间  会做什么"
I ask myself, "What would you do if you had more time?"
仁慈的主  祂把你最想要的赐予了我
The Lord, in his kindness, he gives me what you always wanted
祂赐予我时间
He gives me more time
我在华盛顿特区为华盛顿纪念碑基筹款
I raise funds in DC for the Washington Monument
她讲述我的故事
She tells my story
我公然反对奴隶制
I speak out against slavery
倘若你仍有时间  本可以成就更多
You could have done so much more if you only had time
当生命走到尽头  我是否了然无憾
And when my time is up, have I done enough?
他们会否讲述我们的故事
Will they tell our story?
我能给你看看我最引以为豪的成就吗
Can I show you what I'm proudest of?
孤儿院
The orphanage
我建立纽约第一所私立孤儿院
I establish the first private orphanage In New York City
孤儿院
The orphanage
我帮助抚养数不清的孩子
I help to raise hundreds of children
我看着他们长大成人
I get to see them growing up
孤儿院
The orphanage
我在他们眼中看到了你  亚历山大
In their eyes I see you, Alexander
时时刻刻
I see you every time
当生命走到尽头  我是否了然无憾
And when my time is up, have I done enough?
他们会否讲述我的故事
Will they tell my story?
他们会否讲述你的故事
Will they tell your story?
我等不及与你再会
Oh, I can't wait to see you again
只剩下一点点时间
It's only a matter of time
他们会否讲述你的故事
Will they tell your story?
时间
Time
谁生  谁死  谁讲述你的故事
Who lives? Who dies? Who tells your story?
时间
Time
他们会否讲述你的故事
Will they tell your story?
时间
Time
谁生  谁死
Who lives? Who dies?
谁讲述你的故事
Who tells your story?
字幕总监制  布塔
后期  渔夫
校对  布塔的肝
翻译  肉松
翻译  辰星晓祝2020高考生金榜题名
翻译  伊森泽生
翻译  杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译  子V
翻译  苏葵
翻译  TracyOY
翻译  幽冥部落
翻译  贝七
翻译  Z小花儿
翻译  米糊
翻译  江夏
翻译  余欢
翻译  Giggles
翻译  kathy567
翻译  陈奥奥
翻译  布塔从此不畏歌词
时间轴  浪影JustYouWait
时间轴  知之Dadala
时间轴  嘉嘉Satisfied
时间轴  今NonStop
时间轴  没有影子Dissident
时间轴  西·查MyShot
时间轴  Ans永远爱迪士尼爸爸